You just said something that's like very important can't be dogmatic when you're talking about vaccines or about anything.
Yes it is good to keep an open mind isn't it and be flexible and look at a 360 degree view of things rather than your tunnel vision
and what you're indoctrinated into isn't it?
Yeah and especially if you know that indoctrination has been on purpose and profitable.
One of the great things about your book is first of all your book is called dissolving illusions.
I know I've talked about on the podcast a bunch of times but you also highlight a lot of things that we know are beneficial
that somehow or another get lumped into nonsense like even cinnamon.
Cinnamon is a powerful herb actually and it's known to be helpful in glucose handling for a lot of diabetics taking it in capsule form now.
I noticed at the end of my nephrology career that a lot of my own patients were taking cinnamon capsules but it's also has a lot of vitamin C in it
and I think that was probably one of the keys.
A lot of those old remedies that we wrote about the magic and then probably was the vitamin C in them.
I dismissed all that stuff as total nonsense.