You just said something that's like very important can't be dogmatic when you're talking about vaccines or about anything.
Yes it is good to keep an open mind isn't it and be flexible and look at a 360 degree view of things rather than your tunnel vision
and what you're indoctrinated into isn't it?
Yeah and especially if you know that indoctrination has been on purpose and profitable.
One of the great things about your book is first of all your book is called dissolving illusions.
I know I've talked about on the podcast a bunch of times but you also highlight a lot of things that we know are beneficial
that somehow or another get lumped into nonsense like even cinnamon.
Cinnamon is a powerful herb actually and it's known to be helpful in glucose handling for a lot of diabetics taking it in capsule form now.
I noticed at the end of my nephrology career that a lot of my own patients were taking cinnamon capsules but it's also has a lot of vitamin C in it
and I think that was probably one of the keys.
A lot of those old remedies that we wrote about the magic and then probably was the vitamin C in them.
I dismissed all that stuff as total nonsense.
I was like all that's hippie nonsense like echinacea like get out of here it's hippie nonsense.
Garlic come on get out of here.
Then the more of red things especially like garlic is incredible for staff infections for some reason.
It is and it doesn't develop drug resistance like a lot of the drugs that are engineered for it.
Yeah the hippie seem to have got it right I think.
Well it's just that whole idea of natural remedies is so just universally dismissed by non-silly people.
You know when you say natural remedies that's great if you have a heart attack go to a doctor stupid you know that's generally people's appeal to authority.
But the doctors should be recommending those things too like they're they're good too.
Like vitamin D super important you know vitamin A super important.
And one of the things that you talked about in the book is that I think this is really important when you're talking about the measles vaccine.
You were saying that either if you get an infection with measles just a natural infection or if you get the vaccine you're still going to get depleted of vitamin A.
Like if you get vaccinated for the measles you should be taking vitamin A as well.
Your body is going to get depleted just by getting that shot they don't tell you that.
No they don't tell you anything just Tylenol which actually makes the vaccine not work as well in addition to causing all kinds of immunological disturbances at the time that you're supposed to be up regulating your immune system against this dreaded disease.
Yeah but one of the things about the recommended by the you know the white coats and the authorities is that the public believes that so many drugs and remedies are standardized that the conventional medical system gives out.
And when you go to actually look at them and this includes vaccines even though they're standardized meaning that the manufacturers are told what the regulations should be in terms of production when people go and look at them they find it's anything but standardized.
It's very variable which is why we see such variability in the in the results when people receive them that's only one reason why there's so much variability.
And do you think it's the immunity to any legal consequences that has allowed them to sort of operate like this?
Well we certainly saw an explosion of their creativity since 1986.
So actually in 1986 you're referring to the National Child Vaccine Injury Act that was passed in 1986 but before 1986 we had 1976 which was the swine flu vaccine fiasco.
And that was a situation where there was so much injury that the vaccine producing companies were no longer able to get insurance.
And so they went to the government and they said we need you to indemnify us and they did. And so the government absorbed all the lawsuit cases that happened as a result of the Guillain-Barré that happened from then.
And so that kind of set a precedent for 1986. So back then vaccines were just kind of you know pieces of microbe or maybe a live attenuated virus.
And then they would put a background of all kinds of hard things inside of it and tell you it was just a clear beautiful pure solution but that's beside the point.
So then 1986 comes along because there's so many lawsuits happening because of the Dipliaria Protossus Tetanus vaccine.
That again the vaccine companies couldn't continue to go on the way they were because they were being sued so much.
So then this horrible act was passed which to some people seemed like a good idea.
And this is always how it goes is we're going to make you this promise yes yes yes we're going to we're going to cover all the lawsuits now out of taxes but it's going to be okay because we're going to pay out these lawsuits and you're going to be fine.
If your if your kid takes one for the team you're going to be okay.
And what happens is after time after they get their foot in the door they narrowed down the they basically have a kangaroo court that decides if you're eligible.
And so the qualification tables got narrowed down because in the beginning they were paying out so much of this.
So not only did it make the vaccine companies very very wealthy and indemnify but as you alluded to just a minute ago.
The creativity of the vaccine companies expanded so after that they could add different what we call adjuvants things that stimulate the immune system so the vaccine works better.
Then they start that's why we're able to be in a messenger RNA vaccine situation today which which that wouldn't have happened if it weren't for this indemnification that you know the vaccine trials have always been a bit of a joke but they're even more of a joke today than they were in the beginning and we've never seen a vaccinated unvaccinated study that's that is accepted by the powers that be as you know good enough.
The vaccinated unvaccinated studies that they have they use another vaccine for you probably know that so if you're testing a measles vaccine.
You know you could test it against a diphtheria vaccine or a flu shot vaccine is tested against a hepatitis A vaccine there's no saline placebo because the few studies that exist with saline placebo show how bad the vaccine actually is and how it makes you not only not respond to the disease when it comes around but more susceptible to it in many cases.
Have there been any instances where vaccines have been helpful.
The question of the century isn't it okay now we have to back up a minute because I had that same question and I had to go dig deep to all the questions you have in your head right now I had them to at one point so here I am a medical doctor working in the field believing it pretty much everything I was told giving hundreds of not thousands of vaccines out to my patients.
Hepatitis B vaccines in particular flu shots for sure I was a nephrologist kidney specialist in dialysis et cetera and initially you know we all kind of have an aversion to needles I think it's a natural human if we're just somewhere kids we don't know what's going oh I want to go get my vaccines you know okay fine sore arm you get over it most of us we're lucky enough to get over it.
So by the time the first instance of a problem occurred in front of my eyes I was already a fully seasoned professor of medicine you know working in an a tertiary care medical center okay.
And so it's been a bit of a process because for me it was the influenza vaccines in 2008 2009 that showed me without a doubt that vaccines can and do cause kidney failure and put people on dialysis that that does happen it can cause hypertension.
So we're not told to take a vaccine history in medical school we're not told to even look there it's not even part of especially in adults but when I did start looking there I I started to see more and more associations let's just put it that way and so first I had to go down the flute the flu vaccine bunny trail and every time I went down that flu vaccine bunny trail guess what I was asked what about polio right so I thought right even though this has absolutely zero to do with polio because I'm watching people crap out in front of me after influenza vaccine.
In influenza vaccines let's see about polio because I knew very little about polio just like most people walking around out there do that you know it was invented by this guy named Jonas Salk and it saved humanity we don't see this little crippled kids anymore we don't have iron lungs anymore yay well I would have to say that the polio bunny trail was the darkest one of all and so after polio then became smallpox and I thought you know we still have people walking the earth that have experienced the polio years.
So I kind of like to stick to polio because most of the smallpox you know people that would have been familiar with it are off the planet but there's still some doctors around that will talk about smallpox the guy named Thomas Mac who's probably close to 90 who was kind of ground zero in the 1940s and knows a lot about it and still says we shouldn't be vaccinating for smallpox today.
So then there was that and then everyone in their dog was talking about autism and I didn't really want to have anything to do with autism because I was an adult doctor I think we should break down step by step what about polio yeah everything starts with good health that's why a G1 is a great addition to any morning routine and why partner with them for so long one scoop once a day simple research back and designed to support your whole body health and actually taste great you can forget juggling multiple pills.
And supplements a G1 is a more in one solution that combines a multibitavan superior B complex a blend of super foods and more and more importantly a G1 prioritizes using nutrients that are already in their bioactive form so your body can use them easily just mix it with cold water in your set no hassle no guesswork it's never too late to create a new healthy habit for 2025 so try a G1 for yourself and right now
G1 is offering new customers a free $76 gift when you subscribe you'll get a welcome kit a bottle of D3 K2 and 5 free travel packs in your first box so make sure you check out drink a G1 dot com slash Joe Rogan that's drink a G1 dot com slash Joe Rogan check it out because you said polio once once we've breached that because that's the big one yeah right this is the one that everybody points to we don't have purple kids yeah what
when you look at the historical timeline of polio what do you think caused it to go it's essentially not be a problem anymore okay you don't think vaccinations at anything to do with that well I also it's not what I think because that's the thing like look when I got into this I didn't say oh you know I want to argue that vaccines are great I said look I don't care I didn't have skin in the game I didn't have vaccine injured kids I couldn't care less about it and essentially
accepted it was something in front of me and it didn't make sense so I thought wherever the truth falls that's what I'm going to talk about so what I say is that I what what the facts line up to show you is that polio is still here polio is still alive and well polio is called different things today whereas back in the 1940s 1950s the criteria for diagnosing polio are completely different to the year that the vaccine was introduced that the playing field the goal post everything was changed
so that despite the fact that there was more paralytic polio in the years after that vaccine was introduced they were able to show a complete cascading drop of paralytic polio simply because of the way they change the definitions of what polio is and what could cause it they started testing for the virus or before they would never test for the virus and when they started testing for the virus later what they would find that people had
geombrace syndrome they didn't have virus if they had cock sacky virus or echo virus or they were led poisoned or mercury poisoned which was the mercury and led were the leading treatments of the day including bloodletting they were telling people to put take your cigarette and put a little bit of arsenic in there it's good for your lungs
yeah they were literally blowing smoke up people's butts like that that's where the term comes from because they're if you want to google that now you'll see that there's an instrument that doesn't yeah
so yeah the polio story where to even begin and so there's about 70 pages and so that became my obsession so when people said what about polio when I started digging this up I went deep into it did you dive into pesticides yes yes you have to dive into pesticides because the tonnage of production of DDT absolutely mirrored the the diagnosis for polio in the days and the countries that still make DDT today is where we're still seeing this parallel
to polio situation happen and also weren't the first cases didn't they break out in a rural community the first cases of polio yes
parallel to polio yes it was out in the countryside well that was probably more because of the sheep and cow dipping so arsenic you'd have to look at arsenic you have to look at the mercurials you have to look at the calcium arsenate let arsenate sprays or put on trees but what you're talking about
particularly they would call the cow disease they go out in the family when you would go to the house and say all the kids have the cow disease what the cows had before what were they doing they would have this trench as you talk to farmers even today oh yeah we had trenches we would just walk them straight through and I'd be soaked with the stuff by the end of the day
oh my god yeah so they're basically soaking and bathing and arsenic which is great for killing fleas and ticks but it's not really great for keeping your nervous system happy because the fact of the matter is and this again I've got medical references everything I can do
I can't get away with making stuff up okay I have to put a reference for everything but arsenic causes the exact same spinal pathology that and fevers and everything it literally mimics what they were calling polio and a polio virus back in the day
I read this crazy statistic and I still can't believe it's real that 95 to 99% of all polio is asymptomatic that's exactly right so polio virus is what we call a commensal
just like you have staff on your skin and strep on your skin and it actually serves a purpose it keeps other microbes in check as long as you don't get a cut
and have not a good immune system to deal from the inside out so polio the reason I can say that polio is a commensal is because again there are medical studies that shows that people who dared to get on the edge of some of these wild native tribes down in South America or elsewhere
but in particular I'm talking about South American tribe called the Javante Indians so the Indian Health Service got to the edge of it and bargained that they would get some stool and some blood from the tribes so that they could test it for polio
and what they found was 98 to 99% of every person they tested and it was hundreds of people had all had evidence of immunity to all three strains of polio
and they said to them well where are your crippled children where's your short legs where are the people that died of respiratory failure and they were like we don't have we don't have any of that problem
so it could possibly be that whatever you're calling polio evolved and became less powerful over time and more contagious does that does happen in some some viruses right
most viruses in nature don't become more problematic as they go through the human the human system they become less problematic
remember remember the whole COVID thing like in the beginning people were getting super super sick it was it wasn't as contagious
but it was more virulent and as it attenuated into the human bodies it sort of felt it kind of fizzled out a bit
and then we got the Omicron which was you know less it was more spreadable but it was much less pathological
and that's the natural process that happens so when you're going to have problems real problems with microbes they're usually going to be reverse attenuated meaning made more lethal in a lab
and then they're introduced into the population and look I'm not making this up either 1916 upper east side Manhattan
there was a Rockefeller lab that their their specific stated goal was to try to create the most pathological neuro pathological strain of polio possible
and they did that by taking monkey brains and human spinal serum and injecting it into monkeys and there was a big problem with that which was released into the public by accident
and the world experienced the worst polio epidemic on record 25% mortality that's unheard of really freaked the public out but as it as it cut in that you can see the epicenter as it
fanned out and as it fanned out and as time went on never heard of it again it it attenuates as it moves through the body
because it's a normal human commensal that goes back to its normal state when it's in a human and that's generally what happens
if you have a highly lethal virus and it kills a lot of people those people are dead they can't spread anything
so that's kind of a different story if you want to talk about haunted virus or something like that but as far as polio goes
no polio was only made more lethal by the stupid things that humans did around it so make it more invasive into the body
just like you can go do stupid things and end up with herpes outbreaks and you know staff outbreaks
polio virus is a normal commensal it used to be until we obliterated it with oral vaccines and replaced it with
vaccine strain but the wild strains are normal human commensals
so there's vaccine strain polio that just comes from a vaccine and is transmissible
absolutely today it would be the oral polio vaccines because they're the live strains
and they're still giving them pulse fashion all throughout India they they did a campaign a few
years back in Israel and they always say that a nomad came and you know pooped in the
sewage system and they find it in the sewage system and they don't want an outbreak to happen
so they treat everybody so that's today the most common reason to see polio polio my lightest disease
from a virus if you test for a virus they'll usually find the vaccine virus and that's why today we
don't remember when we were kids because we're about the same age I think they would give us the sugar
cube maybe you didn't but I did I got the sugar cube and that was the live vaccine well they
stopped doing that because after a while the only cases of polio and it became so obvious that
the only cases of polio we were seeing related to a virus when they tested for polio virus were
vaccines strains then they started injecting us again but the early injections caused more
paralytic polio than it prevented and that's the part the people don't understand when they say
what about polio because they they like you just go well there's no more iron lungs there's no
more crippling there's no more these little poor little kids walking around their their cast well
that's that's not true because the iron lung is now called a ventilator so that's out the window
transverse my lightest which there are about 1300 cases I think it's a month diagnosed in one
particular I put a quote put a quote in here on that but transverse my lightest is actually
something that would have absolutely it follows the same pathology as polio would have been
called polio back in the day so we still have polio that we had in 1953 because in 1953 all
you had to have to be diagnosed as polio any maca diagnosed you just one examination with one
set of muscles being paralyzed there was no time frame on it there was no testing done on it
and then it was considered a public service to do it because then you're eligible for funding
so what do they call it again can you say that word again my lightest polio my light polio my lightest
is the definition of the actual pathology you know so it basically means inflammation of the
gray matter of your spinal cord that's what polio and greek polio my lightest it means gray
matter inflammation polio my lightest polio my lightest is is what happens in the body okay if you
want to talk about what causes it then okay maybe in some cases the polio virus causes it
and all the other things we just mentioned arsenic lead arsenate calcium arsenate
injections tons electives were huge cause of some of the worst cases of polio my lightest
and in fact injections and tons electives and unnecessary surgeries were put on hold
during the years were the epidemics were the worst so that's just proof that even the surgeons
knew that why why does it affect it okay so if you happen to have polio my light is circulating
in your body that's not just sitting in your intestines and say it made its way into your body
because we can if things can go from your intestines into your body and you happen to have it
close to a nerve that's up say around your throat and then you go and take a tonsils out
then what you've done is you've given that access to the blood compartment the lymph
compartment and the brain stem which is right there local so those are the people that would get
what was called ball bar polio which is the ones that put you on a ventilator and it's highly
lethal it's one it's the worst kind of polio to get ball bar polio and it was very well known to
have been coincident with tons electives not only that but tons electives changed the structure
and antibodies and the immunity that occurred in the throat and it changed it for the for the worse
not for the better do you think they're unnecessary or is there some times when people have
together tonsils removed or is it just a nonsense practice okay so again it's not it's not just
a cut and dry answer because let's just say that anyone who's ever brought their child to me
because the tonsils were touching or they were snoring has not had to have a tons elect
to me now does that mean that a tons elect to me won't solve that problem where you're snoring
and you know you kids maybe not oxygenate no if you let it go that long probably you're going to
need a tons elect to me but I've seen so many cases reverse it's a very easy thing to do but as doctors
we're not taught about all the things that you were talking about earlier the the natural remedies
but just simply gargling with a solution of sodium ascorbate vitamin C can make a huge difference
because tonsils are like they're like porous golf balls if you want to think of them that way
they've got pits in them and and so food you eat and bacteria and pus can build up but if you
just start rinsing the outsides of them and start nourishing the body from inside and getting
rid of things that the kid might be allergic to which almost every kid's going to eat if your
parent doesn't know better it can make a remarkable difference in these kids that have these huge
tonsils so I think that a lot I think everything else should be done first before taking out the
tonsils if there's time because I'd say 95 to 99% of the time you can prevent that child from
needing their tonsils removed before we go to a smallpox I want to talk about this because you
just brought it up when one of the things that Brett Weinstein has explained to me is that aluminum
is when that the concept is that giving someone a shot with aluminum in it and triggering an
immune immune response if they're eating certain foods during that time they can then develop
an allergy to those foods like certain people with peanuts and various things like that that are
used to be very common for people to eat but then a bunch of people developed like pretty severe
food allergies and he makes this connection that he believes he is as reasonably it's a reasonable
connection to say that there's something absolutely 100% and it's not just something he's dreamed up
again provable medical literature in the book dissolving illusions the physiology the pathologies
known it's very well known that the vaccines that have aluminum in them skew the immune system so
the immune system kind of just if you want to break it down this is really simply you have your
TH1 arm and your TH2 arm your TH1 arm is a really important one those are your T cells you know your
lymphocytes the cells that you know chew up any garbage that's going around that's the part you
want activated in any infection you have whether it's COVID or measles or smallpox or whatever
then you have your TH2 arm which is there mostly to deal with parasites and things like that and it's
mostly an antibody arm of immunity that's the one the vaccinologists are obsessed with making
sure there's enough antibody so though the vaccines that have aluminum in them as opposed to the
live attenuated vaccines which don't have aluminum all the other ones do so your DTA
AP is going to have aluminum in them all your killed vaccines are going to have aluminum in them
and that is very well known to trigger that TH2 response which is the allergic response which
can set up your body for autoimmunity and so part of the part of the purpose of you know
breastfeeding which is part of the the blueprint for humanity and every other mammal
is that the mother is able to introduce antigens in the world to her baby through her own breast
and things that she's been eating and breathing in and then the baby is able to develop tolerance so
you know while vaccine scientists are obsessed with getting antibodies and ramping up an
infants inadequate immune system the fact of the matter is is that it's more important to learn
what not to react to when your immune system is developing rather than to becoming defensive against
every microbe that could get you so that's kind of the paradox there and kind of one of the battle
grounds for you know immunology within immunology and for those of us out here that are going what
are you doing here you know anyway you're also talking in your book about the importance of
breast milk and the the amount of nutrition that's in breast milk for for a child and what it does
for a child and the differences in their immune system the differences in a lot of different
aspects of their development which is pretty fascinating and most people kind of just assume
it's food it's just food but it's a lot more than that it's so much more than that and I was
actually quite startled when I really went down that rabbit hole to see not only I mean it is food
it's it's excellent nutrition with short-chain fatty acids and sugars that the baby needs and
actually trains your gut to be healthy in the long run as an adult which trains your immune system
as well but what that mother is putting through her breast milk you know things like something called
hamlet H-A-M-L-E-T which stands for human alpha lactile human made lethal to tumors and this is a
substance this is a protein it's like a transformer protein that can literally turn into a cancer
busting molecule that is being used by the oncology industry okay and when it's not in that form
it's a powerful protein that fights off pertusses all kinds of pneumococcal bacteria and when
it's not doing that it's food okay so it's like it's got so many different purposes stem cells
are coming through that that mother's milk activated T cells activated T cells have another substance
in them that's that is kind of hijacked by the oncology industry and that is when when they're
immunosuppressing kids for leukemia or whatever and they come in contact say with um chicken pox
what they can do is get somebody like me who's immune to chicken pox naturally and take my
memory T cells that remember that and there's a substance in there um called dializable
leukocyte extract when you put that into another child even if whether they eat it or inject it
into them it transfers cellular that TH1 important arm of immunity I just told you it transfers
it on to them it protects them for a long time so that's kind of in the old days when when
mothers had measles in the old days and normally and they were able to pass this powerful immunity
through that that DLE factor as well as all these other things including preformed immune
globulans um I mentioned something like 80,000 stem cells it's it's just incredible all and we
still have only hit the tip of the iceberg in in terms of what we know about breast milk
but breast milk also it's been proven again that if you're going to if you are going to vaccinate
your baby if you're breastfeeding the vaccine will bring that baby more into a TH1 if you're not
breastfeeding and you're giving formula that baby is going to move more into a TH2 in response to
that vaccine so like if I think if most women understood the powers of breast milk they they
would do everything possible to be able to do it I think you make a very compelling point for that
I just I think it's arrogant that we could assume that we could replace something with about
I mean I've never read the ingredients of formula yeah but how could that be good I know
it parasites we have we have parasites that have been parasites upon humanity for such a long time
and that's what happens is that something is discovered and for some people maybe it can be
a good idea but then the parasites take it and and want to so when it came to breastfeeding it was
you don't have to do that you don't have to bother yourself like that you don't have to pull your
boobs out in public you don't have to become a dairy cow just strap them down the milk will stop
and then you can start putting this wonderful when I was a kid I was fed soy milk in a warm plastic bag
that was the fad then grown up so the the formula industry is a huge money maker and some women do
prefer it fortunately 75% of women in the USA today do initiate breastfeeding so that's very much
better than the polio days when almost nobody was breastfeeding and they were using milk in the
infant formula that had been contaminated by what the cows were eating oh my god and so that was
another part of the polio story that's not been told so the cows were all eating these pesticides
yes and herbicides yes and the cows were getting sick with it and then these people were drinking
the milk from that cow and getting sick as well well the cows wouldn't have been getting
necessarily getting sick from it but it would be concentrating in their milk and so the milk
the milk would have been expressed but what you you just brought me back to another place cows
were also used during the smallpox era and what you're saying is true about that so they would
basically take what they thought what sorry it's just so dark that I sometimes you have to laugh
but they would take pus from other animals scratch it into the belly of a cow then take the pus the
pus off of the the big pimples that would form on the belly of a cow the cow could become very sick
and yet that's cow could still be butchered up at the butcher shop the butcher would get sick with
pempagus or some hand and mouth disease or you know so things that the cows that normally hatch
and so those cows could still be used to produce meat in those cases I don't know that it was used
to produce milk I don't think that would have I don't know but I know it was used to produce meat
because the butchers were getting sick and the people that were eating the meat were getting sick
and certainly the people that took the vaccines that had certain who knows what in them because
it was shown like into the 1970s 80s and even recently I have a reference after the year 2000
that there was more bacteria and fungus in the smallpox vaccines than there was smallpox virus
so it was because they had this thing called pure lymph which was pus that came out of the horse
horse's foot or a donkey's pus skin or or cadaver of a human or a cow's ulcerating
utters and scraped into glycerin and called pure lymph and marketed all over the world as a
said this is the look joke this was our success this is the one vaccine eliminated eradicated
a disease can you believe that fairytale I'll tell you another one like that it doesn't get crazy
this is our success this this vaccine that I have described in great detail with what was in it
and what people saw under microscopes and then later tested genetically was what was called a
quasi species meaning they don't even after a while it became its own thing it wasn't from a horse
anymore it wasn't from a human anymore they called it humanized horsepox when they when they
genetically characterized the driveaxe and then ordered that every driveaxe specimen on the planet
be destroyed I think that was around 2009 why did they do that good question I don't know hiding
the evidence possibly but they now have a new vaccine which doesn't work but they wanted to
bring this one back when I when I was in my the peak of my career in 2003 they I got a letter on my
desk stating that they needed people to get vaccinated for smallpox so that those other people
that were getting vaccinated would have somebody that could treat them that would be immune to small
pox because it's well known that if you get a smallpox vaccine and you get these horrible scabs
that you are going you're going to spread smallpox and you're going to have a horrible itchy
time of it secondary infections you will need a doctor at some point well it turns out that the
trials that they did on super healthy people soldiers that were in top shape were so bad in terms
of cardiac disease and other diseases that the government put it on hold for a second said oh no
no we can't do this meanwhile guess what they were using the same vaccine in the 1700s and 1800s
late yeah 70 late 17 hundreds all through the 1800s into the 1900s they would sometimes you
probably saw the picture the the child's arm considered a good take five huge ulcers on the
arm with sanitation being what it was no antibiotics can you imagine having your baby have five scars
on its arm ulcerating from these things having fevers sometimes the arms became the chronic
sometimes the disease spread all over the place and there was nothing but to give them except
bloodletting mercurials and arsenicals and heating them up in a dark room with no sunlight
that was the treatment for smallpox so you tell me why smallpox was so lethal
this episode is brought to you by farmer's dog it doesn't matter how old your dog is it's always a
great time to start investing in their health and happiness and thankfully the farmer's dog makes
it easier than ever to feed your dog a healthy diet of real meat and veggies dogs prefer their food
even picky dogs and owners prefer their service if you have a question about your dog your plan
your delivery or anything else they have 24-7 customer service that connects you to real humans
who are genuinely interested in providing the best experience possible for you and your dog
they give you detailed instructions on how to transition your dog to fresh food and even pre-portion it
for your dog specific needs feeding your dog healthy human grade food shouldn't be complicated
and with the farmer's dog it isn't the entire experience from box to bowl is a breeze so
try the farmer's dog today and give healthy freshly made food a try you can get 50% off your first
box of food plus free shipping just go to the farmer's dog dot com slash rogan tap the banner or
visit this episodes page to learn more offer available for new customers only well what's
fascinating also is that most people aren't aware of the just the general public health conditions
during the time of the smallpox outbreak that's right and uh uh just the way the way people lived
is almost unheard of you you wouldn't you wouldn't be able to imagine just the smell of human feces
everywhere like streets were filled with outhouses there was animal shit in the streets
it was no sanitation there's no running water it's a disaster it's a disaster and there's no good food
so you got malnutrition you you're exposed to numerous pathogens and just in the waste you
probably have fecal matter on everything it's probably unavoidable attracts in your house it's
everywhere you go it's your drinking water yeah drinking water was a pet you would skim the top off
for your drinking water back then and we know that co-infections make make any primary infection
worse you know if you have measles and you get a co-infection it makes it worse COVID with a
co-infer anything makes it worse you end up with you know pneumonia's and plus pockets in your
lungs so yeah thank you for that description i don't think i could have done it much better myself
but that's that's the that was normal it's go watch gangs of New York like that's that's
obviously a drama and you know it's probably not completely accurate because my bed is pretty
closed yeah it's pretty close down people live back then yeah the slums like you can you can
actually like in here it's not all medical articles articles quoted some of the quotes that we
use are historical quotes from you know anthropologists that would go through the slums in New York
you know the Ellis Island was just bringing people in bringing people in and these they would
sometimes have 20 people in one room with no privy dark you know like you say some of the
the sewage would run underneath the house so the smell of it would be coming up through the
whole time and then you have them working 16 hours a day at the age of anything upwards of
four to five years old could be sent to either coal mines or canneries to bring money in for the
families to barely survive so people weren't being paid very well but you just said smallpox being
what it was but what people don't realize is that in the 1600s late 1680s doctors were describing
smallpox as one of the easiest diseases to treat if you simply just supported the human again quoted
that and then what happened is the industrial revolution and people were taken with the land
enclosure acts out from the farms and brought into cities which didn't have the pigs basically
were the garbage man back then so the pigs ran wild thank god because if they didn't it would have
been even worse horses were your cars so your horse were dumping everywhere you know some people
just they said there was a foot of horse manure to get through to walk across the street so it was
it was horrible and pretty much every way you can think of and and then the human oppression
on top of it in terms of the poverty that was there and the wealthy elite at the top kind of
you know living the good life but it was starting to filter up to them at some point which is why
it was actually individual people that sponsored the first public drinking
fountains and things like that was probably partly to save themselves because if you can
if you can stop disease from running running rampant through society look they still had to go
into the cities to get things right and even if you sent your servant into the city your servant
could bring you home something lovely from the city yeah this is not the picture that was painted
when we were children of what society was like you know we were told that this vaccine was so
important and it was so effective that we don't need it anymore I actually ended up with one when
I was very young I think what we're talking about when we're saying the conditions that these
conditions aren't known to most people and that these conditions coincide with these diseases
and that's probably it's probably not just a correlation so the conditions correlate with the
the with the diseases and the conditions also correlate with the death rates okay and so there
were many of the diseases that were talking say just diarrhea do you know diarrhea killed more
people in the civil war than bullets yeah and lots of other wars diarrhea um diarrhea can be caused
by lots of things nothing that we vaccinate for essentially at that well I mean today this road
of virus but that wasn't a thing then it was more you know typhus and things like that so um and
just getting it from water yeah that's what that would have been because they would be out you know
in the in the in the bush or the trenches you know drinking what they could so um
um redirect me again we're just talking about the um okay so the the diseases that there were
never any vaccines for we see the death rate come down at the same exact avalanche as the diseases
that we did vaccinate for and in some cases there's a little blip when the vaccine comes up and
things get worse for a bit and then come back down so again the point of the book was just interpreting
the data that's existed for a really long time vital statistics throughout the world as to
the decline in death rate in some case the disease rates went down to but the most important thing
was the death rate because that's what people that your baby could die you have to have a vaccine right
it's not your baby could have a rash um you know so different diseases have different
severities and um and different solutions and different ways to treat them so that they never
have to present to a hospital but like you said you know back in those days you know there wasn't
the the pharmacies basically had your mercurials arsenicals if you were lucky some homeopathics
that was pretty much medicine back then until aspirin was invented which was probably one of the
reasons why the 1918 flu looked as bad as it did because they were giving people up to 10 grams
of aspirin a day which can cause pulmonary edema and a healthy person so what was this logic behind
the arsenics and the mercurials like how did that become an approach that they used for medicine
oh well i don't know actually don't know the answer to why they started doing that those are
two really bad things well i'll tell you i'll tell you how they prescribed it as they would say
give one grain until emiscus occurs that means throwing up so give it until a person throws up
because back then they believed that if they could get you to throw up they thought if bringing
stuff out of your body was good bloodletting throwing up and diarrhea and so that's how that
was the threshold for giving a lot of these drugs so they thought instead you know how can you get
someone to have diarrhea with as a doctor okay well we can give them mercurials and arsenicals
that will do the trick and so they thought that they could purge the body by doing that first
think in medicine past present and future yeah okay paradoxically as therapeutic agent that has
been used since ancient times for the treatment of multiple diseases so does it um actually cure
some stuff small doses well well how much is the cure if you have a dead patient or a patient
with neuropathy you haven't really cured anyone haven't right well isn't it dose dependent right
it says arsenic trioxide the active ingredient in the traditional Chinese medicine was shown
to produce dramatic remission of acute palt you could say that wordly ma'am promyl acidic leukemia
thank you yeah similar to the effect of that vitamin A could do it okay uh right trans retinoic
acid so retinoic acid which is vitamin A yeah okay that's interesting there are still a lot of
voices using oncology what's that I'd say it's less risky for vitamin A then arsenic I mean
that's a different type of arsenic slightly different kind of arsenic or a lower dose of arsenic because
that uh they would they measured things in grains back then so I I guess that's probably like maybe
like a milligram something like that but the Chinese medicine it's probably the root of it right
why they thought it was medicine could be um and maybe they use the wrong arsenic or that's possible
I guess you you start trying the things that you have right mercury is a crazy one though
haven't they known that's poison forever like isn't that quick silver though
these but in the same thing or no I don't know it's a fascinating metal because it's liquid it's a
liquid metal yeah a lot of people played with it when they are kids I know some of the smartest
people I know talk about how they played with the mercury ball when they were little yikes um
and it's in thermometers and obviously it works quite well there's there's a use for mercury
but the reason that um that that it's put into the it was actually in the MMR vaccines and some
of the flu vaccines is because it's an antimicrobial they'll kill everything so maybe that was part
of that because it will kill everything will kill the microbes in a petri dish so in order to because
this is one of the realities of vaccine manufacture which I want your audience to understand on
is that vaccines while it might look like just a clear liquid in order to make a vaccine you have to
have either a cow that you put ulcers on and scrape the pus off um or you can evolve it as it
had evolved to um maybe getting um you know some tumourous cells that came out of a cockroach
spannules kidney or monkey balls or uh or monkey kidneys and you plate those cells out and then you
inoculate it with what you want to grow to put in your vaccine later but in order to keep those
cells alive you have to put animal blood on it you have to put different nutrients on top of it you
have to put antibiotics canemisin you know things like that related to the covid here mercury okay so
in the end you can kill you can make sure when you have your final product that if you put a little
bit of mercury in there that it's less likely for any of the fungus or the spores or the bacteria
or the adventitious viruses that you didn't know about that were there before will be in your final
product wonderful so you have a product now that you can be not completely sure has any of these um
deadly microbes but now has mercury which the only places it's actually okay to have on on the
planet mercury is in vaccines your tooth or toxic landfill so if you were to drop a vaccine
at a vaccine clinic onto the floor the hazmat guys were coming you you're not allowed to just
pick it up if it's got to if it's a mercury containing vaccine the hazmat people have to come
and take that away yet we're okay to take you know set a portion of that vial and inject it into
you know child a three month old child how does that work it doesn't sound logical
and then there was also the the issue with the different types of mercury right there was
is it methyl and ethyl the two different yeah apparently ethyl is good and methyl is bad according to
Paul off it well senior vaccine scientist but the fact of the matter is once once mercury is
methylated and like fish fish can methylate mercury and they can get rid of it once we de-methylate
mercury it's it's in us until you do something like something called chelation where you can put
a chemical into the body that can grab onto it pull it out through your urine otherwise you
stuck with it so in my opinion all mercury's bad shouldn't be put into human shouldn't be in our
food sources shouldn't be in our environment except for in the net look you can even find uranium
in nature right it's what people do to it to concentrate it and how they use it that becomes a
problem wasn't the the issue that one of them I don't know what's methyl or ethyl mercury leaves
the body quicker yes it's ethyl mercury that leaves the body quicker because methyl is a it's a
it's a chemical that gets put onto it naturally and apparently I'm not an expert on mercury poisoning
but apparently methyl mercury we don't have the ability to excrete but ethyl mercury we do
yeah but wasn't there also an issue that it crosses the blood-brain barrier well anytime there's
inflammation anything can cross the blood brain barrier with the it's the aluminum that we really
know crosses the blood-brain barrier and that's still in vaccines today and yeah anybody we get
into blood-brain barrier if you want to that's a whole other story but yeah so mercury obviously
it can get into the brain it's it's found in the brain it can get into you know your adrenals
and your other glands and important areas of your body and even the thing is that even at such low
levels can cause problems no neurotoxin there's no has no place for circulating or being deposited
in the human body in any form but isn't it fascinating that they've done such a good job
promoting this that people are going to get outraged at what you're saying they've done such a good
job and you've got a lot of courage and I want to commend you for that because writing that book
and and being here talk you about it takes a lot of courage and it's from regular people who want
to believe the vaccine they're scared here than anybody the people that are just rabid
vaxers and they want they they stand for science like they're the warriors for science and they get
very aggressive about it and they don't even want to breach the subject they don't even want to
look at it because the more you look at it if you're a logical rational person without like a
deep-seated ideology attached to vaccines and you just look at the reality of it you just go what
what is this like how did you trick people and do injecting
what how many a year now for kids what is it in the seventies we're in the set I believe we're in
the seventies that's insane yeah that's and then you want to demonize anybody who says anything
about vaccine side effects you're the craziest of kooks they come down you with the hardest
publicity campaign it's so transparent you see it coming a mile away and you're still shocked
by how blatant it is and no one wants to look at the actual issue itself and no one wants to say
like well is she right if you read your book you're is she right if you're right and I think you're
right like we've been lied to and we've been tricked into thinking that this is all settled science
and that's what's infuriating it's not that it's anti-science it's like this is not science what you
guys are doing it's not science you've subverted you've you've perverted that notion
and you've you've done an amazing way I mean hats off to you what the what they've done in terms
of like brainwashing people to believe that all this is it's not just necessary but it's saved
millions of lives in anybody that is against it in any way shape or form is a quack and you should
be de-platformed and never talked about again and polite public society and cocktail parties
he'll be shunned yeah well the way they were able to get away with it is 226 years worth
the propaganda because the fact of the matter is that ever since the beginning of the smallpox
vaccines there have been vaccine deaths the reason and look we we've added I brought you a
a special copy this is a limited edition in the 10th anniversary edition we added 200 pages
we added a chapter called the white plague the white plague is also tuberculosis tuberculosis
was a side effect of the of smallpox vaccine tuberculosis rates were rampant and in fact the
inventor of the smallpox vaccine his child died of tuberculosis and so did his to test subjects
that he used and it was well known to follow smallpox lots of doctors talked about it but
in in about two or three years after the vaccine was accepted in in England you hear doctors
speaking out about it cursing the day they ever agreed to do it to people to children to anybody
and so what happened is that the government came down harder and started making it mandatory and
would take your furniture away and started intimidating the doctors and that's an age old thing
as well and I experienced it in any doctor that's ever stepped out of of of line and said something
bad about vaccines will either be intimidated or worse so two under 20 years of prop two under 26
years of propaganda and and so I'm just going to give you one example and I'll give you a copy of
this to have and you can put it up later if you want but in 1984 because there was so much
so much going on in terms of the public learning about the problems with the diphtheria tetanus
pertussis vaccine and the polio vaccines that a federal register was issued by the government and
went to all health departments in the United States which is supposed to just kept there and never
circulated and it said quote any doubts whether or not well founded about the safety of the
vaccination program must not be allowed to exist that's literally what it said it's straight out of
children and so you had that then you have the changing of the goalpost and the
app outright lies within scientism because it's not science it's a religion that that's calls
itself science and we still are a victim of that today most science today is sponsored by the very
people that are going to profit from it and and I think and even look even Jenner who invented
the smallpox vaccine never did a scientific study he never did a controlled study he never did
non-vaccinated people vaccinated people and then expose them to smallpox and in a large enough
group he would cowpox them and then expose them to smallpox and it was well known that smallpox
followed cowpox so it's just been look again I never expected to be here I just wanted to be
healer I just wanted to be a doctor I wanted to be a nephrologist and teach medical students and
make the world a better place for people that's all I ever wanted this is a nightmare for me actually
to while while I've met some incredible people and and I've had a really good life and I have no
regrets and I would do it all again no doctor wants to be put in a position where their integrity is
doubted their sanity is doubted and if you want to pull up a page called it is called
rational wiki I think maybe wikip anyway I'm considered as a Sith Lord a very and in fact I
didn't know what a Sith Lord was back then I had to actually look it up some like Darth Vader so
a bit it was a bit of a compliment but on the other hand most doctors can't tolerate being called
quacks or having the reputation destroyed and you know I went from treating the CEO of actually
the head of the laboratory at my hospital for hypertension to be coming you know somebody that
was doubted on every levels after a while because of one thing that I said which was can we stop
giving vaccines to my sick patients to people who are having chemotherapy while they're having
chemotherapy to my patient before I've even seen them on the ward can we just can we just hold
this up and give it to them on the day of discharge that was my request in the beginning that's how
this all landed here and had they not tried to intimidate me doubt me and pushed me to research and
show that what I saw was actually real I would still be locked up working as a regular doctor because
there were some good things about it so the look even if you look at what happened with COVID let's
just look at that like how did how did they pass this off look at the media today you know that
they're giving COVID vaccines to six-month-old children now we know how bad is we know that it ruined
stem cells and pregnant women they don't give stem cells to their babies the industry's upset because
the placenta's no longer have stem cells and they used to use those stem cells in research and
cosmetics etc they're not getting them anymore because what the COVID shots did to the placenta's
and those infants that's not being talked about in the media nothing bad about the shots being
talked about when we have Kevin McCurne and all these people looking at it goes as SV40 in it
there was a staffel cockle endotoxin gene there were two snake genes in there
you know it's a definite gain of function nope we got to put it on the vaccine the baby vaccine
schedule because any doubts whether or not well funded about the vaccination must not be allowed
to exist that's why that sounds like a religion it sounds like a cult it sounds like a crazy cult
that the whole world's been sucked into giving a COVID shot to a baby today is insane three of them
they get three by the certain I you'd have to look up the schedule but I believe it starts at six
months and they get three of them kind of boom boom it's just really recommending this it's it's on
the it look there's there's a group of people called ACIP the doctors usually with with um vaccine
interest in their bank accounts that make the recommendations for the vaccines and they've
recommended that that that six month old so if your doctor is following the ACIP program you have
to be offered that vaccine and now that doctor this is another part of the story is that doctors
likely to lose 250 thousand dollars a year if they don't do that because there's incentive given to
hospitals and doctors which is what naively I was on the other end of when I woke up in 2008 and
said wait a minute why are we doing this stuff to my sick inflamed patients you're giving more
inflammation um it's because the hospital would lose something like 40 thousand dollars if they
didn't give a vaccine within the first 24 hours of admission oh my god and they would get 40 thousand
if it it was all a money game that's really the bottom line of it and I didn't know that until a
nurse years ago uh who was a high level administration she said she said she said this is why they do
they did that to you oh wow okay well at least it makes sense now nobody wants to think of it as a
business there nobody wants to think you're making business decisions at the expense of someone's
health and possibly whether or not they make it like what do you what are you doing well that's been
the case since you know basically the the medical profession was infiltrated in the early 1900s by
you know high level interests that that didn't want us thinking for ourselves and carrying on with
the natural cures that actually work carrying on with normal midwifery there was just so many changes
that happened as a result of best practice medicine not to mention you know the forming of the AMA
by a couple of real quacks um that's a really good story and the AMA would give their stamp of approval
so say you created an infant formula well they would say AMA approved and your infant formula
would sell even better or remember when doctors smoked camels because camels were bad
those were the case and this is also the time when this coincides with when Rockefeller was designing
the school system right well first Rockefeller I think oil was one of their primary so that's the
farm so investments that's right yeah oh so you want to go school so no but he did both right he
was a part of both so he was a part of the he the reason why natural cures are so easily dismissed
and why so dismissed because Rockefeller put the entire medical establishment on oil based
that's right so all pharmaceutical drugs that are made by using oil yeah and he did it because
he sold oil you know that one of the ironies it kind of works yeah yeah like I got I got rid of a
really bad case of mange in a dog by kerosene but in kerosene diluted in olive oil and they'd been
through everything they could not get rid of this mange on this beautiful dog oh wow that's crazy
it's a dog and yeah so mage is horrible for dogs oh really bad but one spray it was done
I had a dog that I picked up yeah keep careful around the like you know flames and stuff
I had a dog that I picked up off the street and took her in and she had horrible mange but it all
went away with just food I just gave her healthy food no we can't joke come on you had to have
an expert help you no kerosene no nothing just love food oh that was an argument I had in the
hallway once with the senior chief of medicine he was he was like he would always say so how are you
today normally be like good you know superficial confidence I said by the way I'm having real trouble
with you know the h1n1 vaccine my patients getting kidney failure after getting it and he turned
dark on me I never saw him dark before and he said no that just didn't have time to take effect
and of course then I heard every kind of sound bite in the book from him which I didn't know
where sound bites at the time and then he said well what do you think has happened with men
and gyrus and these these college kids I'm like oh come on that's a total no brainer it's like
their nutrition goes down the tubes when they leave home they're smoking they're staying up all
night long they're hanging out with their pals they're doing everything they couldn't do when
they were oh you got to be kidding me so you think it's their food that's that's causing problems
and I was like well what medical school did you go to like I was actually taught that nutrition
matters and how it matters and why it matters but that's been almost completely threat like if you're
if you want to sneak a vitamin C into somebody's hospital room you know the best way to do it
don't bring in jar vitamin C because they will stop that at the door you get yourself a McDonald's
milkshake or a burger and you just dump that milkshake out and you put something else in there
smoothies with some vitamin C and they will say off you go that's perfectly fine that's going to
be great for this person this child that's how you can get it in because they think that McDonald's
is wonderful in fact McDonald's are kind of situated proximal to a lot of hospitals and the McDonald's
Ronald McDonald's houses are there and everything else but bring in a homeopathic or you know
magnesium or vitamin C and you've got to get permission for it and go through so much red tape
and a lot of time you'll be told no you can't give it because oh you'll cause bowel in the
process you'll cause diarrhea you'll cause kidney stones everything in the book that doesn't
actually happen with vitamin C but it's what most look they've measured vitamin C levels on people
that enter hospitals and pretty much everybody's deficient or on the border of deficient when they
enter and pretty much everybody when they leave has got borderline scurvy I've not full full
scurvy fortunately they go home and start doing other things and can rebuild some of their vitamin C
scores but there there's a there's a lot of subclinical scurvy walking around out there and those
are the people that are going to do the worst with the vaccine and then the worst they're going to
do the worst with subclinical scurvy in modern society just from poor diet well you know it's not
just the poor diet so any kind of stress will consume vitamin C cigarette will consume 75
milligrams of vitamin C and they tell you that you only need 190 milligrams a day that's the FDA
requirement so you just have a few cigarettes and you've depleted your your stores so we don't
make our own vitamin C as humans humans and guinea pigs you know that's we don't we don't do that
and so we have to consume it and we're reliant upon our fruits and vegetables or supplements to do
or if you eat organ meat you can eat the adrenals are loaded with it but aside from that your fruits
and vegetables that are going to give it to you so if you're under a lot of stress or you're
taking medication or you have a lot of inflammation or arthritis whatever that's going to consume
vitamin C because vitamin C is an antioxidant as well as an antiviral and you know good for your
nervous system so yeah most people are walking around skimming the the edge if you have you can
see kind of a red line on some people's gums they're probably vitamin C deficient if your gums
are bleeding a lot when you floss you probably need some vitamin C and you know you could have
an infection too but it will deal to the infection as well as the integrity and the collagen inside
of your bones and your soft tissues I mean it's like one of those things that's so important it
should be given upon admission to every hospital and what's really crazy is if you're one of those
people that thinks that all you need is a balanced diet and you're eating like a piece of chicken
and some lettuce yeah like that there's no vitamin C and any of that are not enough probably not
enough yeah not enough you know if you're if you're not consuming like some sort of light
pysomal vitamin C supplement if you're not taking something on top of that you're probably not
at an optimal level to survive anything which is it's also it's like part of why we have so many
metabolic diseases we have bad metabolic health we have metabolic diseases like they shit it should
be super obvious like oh everyone's like really unhealthy doesn't have any nutrients in their system
and they're all getting really sick from all these different things yeah huh yeah but everyone's
like no you need medicine you need a shot you need a this you need a that you need to get on this
you need to get off that and get back on this and you're a hippie if you want to just eat kiwi
fruits and get your vitamin C from that or have oranges or broccoli oh my gosh broccoli makes you
a total hippie or kale you forget about it that's that no see we have a different kind of malnutrition
today then then we describe in the book back then it was people were toxic from basically drinking
poop water and being being worked to death and having diseases all around them and so they were
protein calorie malnutrition as well as vitamin as well today we have kind of disnutrition you
know like D.Y.S disnutrition and that everyone's fat so you don't they don't really look malnourished
pretty much you know you you go on a cruise or you go to the beach you go to bird christmas house
bellies now big belly is the thing what was that I said go to bird christmas house who was that
my friend okay I hate that you don't know yet but you know so today we've got inflamed guts from
you know glyphosate and you know the wheat that's been altered to make us inflamed and and then just
the chemicals that are added to our food and the vitamins that actually don't help us and set us
back that are fortifying our you know bread and milk lack of vitamin D so we have a different kind
of a problem but essentially causing the same bodily dysfunction yeah the wheat thing I used to
think was nonsense until I ate pasta and bread in Italy and I was like okay why do I feel so much
better yeah why do I not feel like I just ate poison because I love like pizza oh yeah I love it
I love lasagna oh I love it I love it it's so good but after it's over I'm like I'm incapacitated
for like an hour or two for like a two-hour period you're just like a shadow of yourself just
you think oh maybe it's just the high carbs but you just proved that it wasn't because in
Italy you were okay with it I ate a whole pizza in Italy and I was waiting for it I was like I'm
gonna eat this margarita pizza it's so good I just made it brick oven I was like this is so good
I'm eating the whole pizza I don't care I don't care what it's gonna feel like afterwards I ate
that whole pizza and then I was like where is it is it coming it never came never came I felt
normal I felt like I just ate food I was like this is nuts like no crash yeah the bread and
Scandinavia same that's what people used to eat people don't know that what's that I said that's
what people use it is like real real food people they need to understand like what they did was
and this is according to a Maynard from tool you know Maynard Keenan the lead singer of tool
no he actually runs a farm he has vineyards and he has like like he's caduceus is his wine label
and he's like really good at growing things because he has a restaurant he was explaining to me
that what they did is they just engineered it to have higher yield so they put more it's got more
complex gluten in it so it's not the normal organic wheat that grows in Italy where they don't
have genetically modified crops right so you can still get that flower and you can still get that
pasta from Italy and it's much more consumable yeah but the American stuff is just it's just your
body's like what is this it just comes in like sludge it feels like I ate glue that's what always
feels like yeah unless it's really good sourdough bread that doesn't seem to have that yeah yeah
kind of like I'm not gluten sensitive but I I definitely feel more awake when I don't have it
yeah it's not good on holiday but it's so delicious yeah no I know it's so delicious but this
is also a problem and this goes back to when RJ Reynolds was going through all their stuff with
the lawsuits that were coming from people realizing oh my god cigarettes give you cancer they're not
good to like smoke if you have emphysema I thought they were good for at some arsenic and it'd be great
there was a movie and I forget what movie it was and thank you for smoking well there's that
okay there was a movie where Leonardo DiCaprio was young and he was sick and his doctor was
prescribing cigarettes to him no and like the mother was saying did you smoke your cigarettes at
the doctor told you you're like you're not smoking like you need to keep up your health like well
you know there's something to that because you know about the nicotinic receptors and you know
the smokers got less covid than the rest of us and I did hear about that well also it doesn't
nicotine kill covid like people were saying that nicotine no so that's what it is that's how it
kills it so what happens so so the spike of covid just the evil part of covid has all these
horrible lab engineered proteins encoded into them and two of them are snake talks and proteins
that bind on to your nicotinic receptors okay so if you can smoke nicotine or take nicotine gum
then you're gonna block those receptors up so that so you can trade off some of the stuff that's
what about like nicotine pouches yeah like that would probably if you're having you know
long covid or you know any kind of post-COVID syndrome that's related to the nicotinic receptors
you only know by trying it but listen I always say start small don't go out and be a hero and
you know take a whole dose at once start with a quarter of whatever it says and wait and see
what happens yeah because nicotines a powerful drug try cigar pick up the cigar yeah there you go
that's a wonderful habit yeah that was a an uncomfortable thing in the beginning of covid
they were saying that for some reason smokers seem to be having a much easier go of it like what
how do you have a respiratory disease where smokers are statistically speaking getting less covid
yeah I mean I've been around I did a tour one time and there were two heavy heavy smokers on
the bus with me and they were the only two people that didn't come down with whatever flu with
all the rest of us got that not even that flu could even live in their throats it's kind of
makes sense if you think about it well changes the polarity of your mucus membranes the charge of
the cells on your mucus membranes and that's probably part of why that even the viruses can't adhere
properly we're not encouraging cigarettes no we're not at all but we are saying but if you are
this should be non-cured naturally cured oh like American spirits like those kind of deals I get
all my smoking friends to convert to that brand does that help totally come on are you kidding me
you know how many horrible carcinogens there are you know back in the native days when they were
smoking and people were smoking natural cigarettes was almost unheard of for them to develop lung
cancer right with a natural tobacco American spirit cigarettes are not they're absolutely wrong
it is a market is natural and additive free which may lead people to believe that they are
safe for option however there's no scientific evidence to support this claim they may even have
higher levels of nicotine than some other brands but the nicotine is not the problem so that's
exactly right just by them saying that there that leads me to think that this might be propaganda
because saying the nicotine is not the problem that that's or rather saying that they have
why have more nicotine but I understand but AI should understand that nicotine
cliff oh I know I know he does I'm just saying AI doesn't make sense what doesn't make sense is
that it's saying they might have more nicotine but that doesn't matter they're not addressing
natural questions time the same times we don't have to go through oh no no I'm not saying to you
I'm just saying to them like with with their writing seems to kind of be silly marketing of American
spirits as natural can create a false sense of healthiness which may make it more difficult for
people to quit smoking I think smoking companies wrote this I think the other companies fed
this information but the packages have the people spitting up blood on the packages and stuff do
you see in England you get the know they have it now he oh they have an America here they used to
have an American in England you go to England and they had photos of people with like right that's
right first thought but it's moved to the rest of the I know it's hilarious it's like and they still
buy them and smoke well the interesting thing is and I'm glad you brought this up it's just cancer
in general like there's things that cause cancer that they're just everywhere and there's a lot
of things in the environment can cause cancer but sometimes things get into medications it can
cause cancer and what is what is SV 40 I just wrote down SV 40 while you were talking and I'm
going I'm just going to give you an example of what you're saying is correct and the fact of the
matter is that all cancers in humanity have gone up since the inception of vaccination and my
opinion my educated opinion is that our lifespan should be 120 years and I think with the knowledge
that we have and the wealth that we have on this planet ingenuity we have on this planet we should
be able to be touching the 120-year mark more commonly than we do so when vaccines started
coming into humanity we were we started introducing animal disease into humanity through the skin
and then we started doing inter muscular injections after the hypodermic needle was created
and then you started to having deeper injections of of animal disease and of chemicals and and
mercurys and things like that so along comes polio research and the polio vaccine even to this day
is made on African green monkey kidney cells now the African green monkey kidneys early on were
basically taken out of their wild habitat in India and millions of monkeys were brought to the USA
for use unbeknownst to them and discovered by a scientist named Dr. Bernice Eddie is that there
was a cancer causing entity inside of the the substrate that they were using to make the vaccine
on the petri dishes and that entity was simian virus 40 SV 40 and called SV 40 because before
there were 39 others discovered before it now we're up over 100 so that information was suppressed
heavily Bernice Eddie was offered a ticket to wherever she wanted to go and as much money she
wanted and she said no I'm staying long story short as they just kept taking her away from her work
and distracting her and there was another doctor Jay Anthony Morris as well anyway so the SV 40
was around and then Maurice Hilleman validated it later and said it came from the African green
monkey kidneys now it's benign in the African green monkey SV 40 it is not benign in human beings
in human beings it was called the perfect war machine by Dr. Michelle Carboni who was one of the
primary researchers looking at the carcinogenic potential of simian virus 40 so simian virus 40 would
have been in the live polio vaccines because there was nothing to kill it but it was more most
likely also in the killed and African green monkey cells are actually still a listed ingredient on
vaccines so you can go ahead and look that up it's a fact so how this affects me is that I'm a
kidney specialist and I looked at the curve of kidney cancers that have gone up since the inception
of polio vaccines and SV 40 introduction so what this virus does it is it enhances two
cancer promoting genes and it inhibits two cancer suppressors okay that's why it's called
the perfect war machine so that was in the vaccines that were injected and so the bad news is that
we don't need vaccines to give it to us anymore because we're going to give it to each other forever
and it's never going anywhere that was introduced to humanity like a lot of other diseases were
through vaccination we can give it to our kids we can give it to each other comes out in the urine
and so it lives in the green monkey kidneys it lives in our kidneys as a kidney specialist there
are a lot of mysterious diseases low and behold there was some research into some of them and the
research was just put this is the other thing the research that that's really important just gets
killed the funding gets killed in terms of SV 40 kidney cancers there's no doubt that the rate of
kidney cancers has gone up alongside with the with the infection rate of humanity for SV 40 as well
as diseases like glomerular nephritis which they do find the pathogen genetic material inside
and they end even in the old days they found it in the tumors but not the surrounding areas so that
just tells you that it was a stimulant for the tumor cells to just start propagating so that's
that's just one of the things that that's just one of many many the obvious ones and even though
it's been well-defined in the medical literature you will see still see that they only admit that it
causes mesotheliomas and one other thing not that it causes all the other things that it does
that it's been shown to cause in the other medical literature that got its funding revoked
so SV 40 is now contagious amongst people absolutely yeah so we probably both have it
most of us probably have had it one time or other you know whether it's lying dormant in our
kidneys it depends on it'll everything depends on your background immunity which depends on
what you're doing for fun and not fun and how you're eating and how much you're sleeping etc how
much sun you're getting sweating sweating gets rid of a lot of stuff it's really good to sweat
it's just such a disturbing thought that this was introduced to people through vaccines and now
is spreading and what is the what's the like the worst health impact that it could have if it
spreads to you and not through a vaccine if you didn't get it through this vaccine and you just
get it from another person like oh it's the same thing it's not going to make much difference
in terms it'll it'll gravitate to your kidneys obviously it probably goes to lung as well
brain brain tumors were a big problem with it back in the polio days dr Michel carbony was
looking at the brain tumors with that there's a really good book called the virus in the vaccine by
bookchin and schumacher it's an incredible book that details everything about those years the
scientists involved the suppression the oppression the lies the skull doggery then they would
bring in the scientists who had no experience in actually detecting SV 40 and lo and behold he
couldn't find it and he was the one that got to make the ultimate statement on whether
SV 40 causes human disease or not there's how could they keep injecting that into people if they
know this oh and this the stocks that contained SV 40 were still basically being used by the vaccine
manufacturers up into the 1990s and probably beyond because there's two different kinds of SV 40
you're making me remember a whole bunch of things that I thought I forgot but there's the
there's the fast dividing and there's the slow dividing there's two different kind of strains of it
and the original tests though when they made a vaccine they would test it for 14 days looking for
SV 40 if it didn't have it off you went your your vaccine was good to go but the problem is there
was a slower dividing SV 40 that remained in the vaccines that were injected and probably in the
stocks that are the stock is basically like your your your mother tincture or whatever it's what you
used to kind of inoculate all the new batches over time and so the stocks were found that again
quote dr. um terny Stanley cops quote in the book about the SV 40 still being in the stock up
and through the 1990s and you know god only knows if there's if it's still if they're still using
those same stocks I don't know because I haven't gone into to the more modern times of SV 40 but
yeah we all have it and there's no doubt in my mind that it's just like another one of the things
that the parasites have finally pretty much put into us to set us back demons it's like like real
world demons it's so crazy that someone would know this and still have this as an ingredient in a
vaccine well they'll say that it was it was just an unfortunate set of events that happened because
they took wild monkeys from India let's see I could work for them that's their excuse and they
say we cleaned it up you know we started our own monkey colonies and we started breeding our own
monkey colonies that were now found to be free of SV 40 the only problem with that is that as I
said they had already inoculated humanity and and it's it's with a virus that can be spread
vertically and horizontally as the scientists would describe meaning we've all given it to
each other um I think they're going to be very few people walking around today that haven't been
introduced to it have there ever been a comparison of um pre cancer rates pre SV 40 and post
SV 40 yeah that's what I'm talking about that's what I did is I I I'm one of my videos I did that
and and looked at the cancer rates since they were you know so again what they'll say is well we
just didn't look at the rates beforehand but the the rates were quite low before like you can
you can know what the surgical what the nephrectomy's were so it's kind of an easy thing to look at
because that's the treatment for kidney cancer you take the kidney out um because you got another
kidney and it's a slow growing tumor even though it can metastasize but anyway um I did look at and
look the the the the the rate has skyrocketed for kidney cancers pretty much everybody knows somebody
who had a kidney cancer and that was not common no and also these protein losing diseases which is
again it's not controversial it was documented when they looked at the the areas that were affected
in the kidney which with with these horrible disease that makes people lose the proteins that need
to stay in their blood in their body out into their urine that the SV 40 was related to that it's
called focal and segmental chlomerular sclerosis and it's a real problematic disease in children
and adults ultimately you have to go on horrible chemotherapy drugs that ruin your immune system
and then transplantation if you can't stay on top of it big money maker now do I think that
that was the purpose i look i don't know what was in the hearts and minds i don't know what was
accidental what wasn't but i do know that there was intentional suppression of the truth
any doubts whether or not well fun it must not be allowed to exist that is a fact and it's always
been that way and there have been scientists and doctors talking about that since the beginning of
vaccination it's just too horrible to believe for most people i think and then also you're correct
it goes against religious dogma you know especially with people that are like firmly on the left
yeah trusting the science and trusting the experts those are those are two things at the front
it's kind of a childlike situation that humanity in most of humanity is in is that there you know
I think most people are good and they want to believe everybody else is good and they want to
believe that the government is looking out for them and it's really it's a kind of horrifying
imagine if it was true that your government actually wasn't looking out for you and that might
be one of the causes of your decreasing lifespan imagine that if the government might not care so
much if your baby ends up with no stem cells or your baby gets cancer autism which will be
outraged and i mean look at autism hello like do we how many i think we're to start with that
but that was another thing where there was no doubt whether or not well funded allowed to exist
what came to autism and every autistic parent parent of an autistic child will tell you this everyone
it's tried to lobby and get to the truth with autism will tell you that the brick walls and the
plexiglass and the lead walls that went down were intense and still are intense and the the
lying studies that they used to uphold vaccine don't cause autism are so easy to dismantle
but you know joe you know the lie gets around the earth three times before the truth has a chance
to get out of bed and and that's just pretty much what happens when the media is owned and like
you're you're like one of the cracks in the matrix here quite frankly i think for a lot of people
it's too horrible to believe especially if they have an autistic child that this was caused by a
vaccine i know a guy who told me that he believes the vaccine had an impact on his child
having autism and then later was shaming people for not taking the covid vaccine
that's how strong the impulse is and that's how good the propaganda was
and that's how cowardly a lot of people are when it comes to fighting against a narrative
they get very scared of being socially ostracized and they just they can't speak their mind they
can't tell the truth and they'll whisper it to maybe this one guy that their friends with like hey
you know i don't want to take it man but i have to for work like yeah i don't i don't trust them either
but you know don't tell anybody i said that yeah you don't want anybody thinking you're on the
bad side and we all saw the propaganda on television there's some amazing montages that people
put together lately of people saying horrible things about the vaccinated people unvaccinated people
horrible things saying that it's uh it may be ghoulish to laugh when unvaccinated people
die but it might it might be necessary like what yeah if you have us have to take one for the team
it's it was just the weirdest propaganda campaign and people were doing the job of the man
it wasn't the man forcing the people to do this thing it was people doing the job of the man
and going after the people that hadn't stepped in line and i think for a lot of people it's like
they felt terrible that they had to do it but if they did it now i'm righteous now i'm on the good
side why don't you do it too man i fucking did it you should do it too you're fucking soulfish
you get a lot of that you know you get a lot of people who they know they made a mistake and they
want you to make that mistake too you know yeah would be good to know what really goes through their
heads i i think covid was again it was unique um but when you talk to parents who have autistic
children the vast majority of them not only know absolutely without a doubt that their child
became autistic usually within 24 to 48 hours after a certain vaccine but that every doctor told
them it wasn't the case and then they go digging deep into the scientific literature and learn how
to sometimes resuscitate that child's brain or detox them and then recover them and then they're
they're they're actually beaten up even worse for doing that because just because they're just
neurodiverse you know there's nothing wrong with your child they're just quirky no your child
banging its head against the wall walking around the baby bottle and a diaper at the age of 18 your
big hairy son doing that that is not neurodiverse quirkiness that is a serious pathological disease
that probably could have been dealt to at the time and should have been prevented should have never
happened so most parents that have that situation are on fire it's the it's a minority that will say
have the situation that you have right now most of them that's a wake up call which is why they get
beat up and suppressed even worse than I do but when it comes to covid there was the the psychological
campaign I think was was very effective in that people that I would have never imagined took the
jab like friends of mine who I in a million years would have I would have bet my life that they
would say no to it ended up getting it didn't want it we're really upset about it later but nonetheless
did they read your book yes I see I didn't lose any friends during covid because I already lost
them back in like two thousand nine like my family and friends were solid my tribe is here but
yeah so did but I still love this person yeah and and and she's like really upset about it but it's
like it just shows you that the psychological campaign like to to get into that person's brain was
was really into like but I don't know about you but there was I never had it down I never I
I was like well you're going to shut me down shut me down you know sought me from traveling go
head slot me from traveling I hadn't read your book yet and I was all gung ho to get the vaccine
and the UFC had allocated 150 something vaccines for all their employees were doing shows during
the pandemic so I showed up in Vegas asked for the shot they said I couldn't do it I had to do it
on Monday at the clinic I couldn't do it at the UFC I was like okay fine and they said can you
come back in two weeks and do it when during the next UFC fight I said fine I'll do it then during
that time it got pulled for the market for blood clots which one which jab Johnson Johnson okay
and then two people I knew who got it at strokes okay in that two weeks yes well you got a few
angels don't you yeah and I was like hold on and then on my whole family got it there was like a
bunch of things that happened my whole family got it and everybody was fine and I didn't get it
and I was trying to get it like I had sex with my wife I hug my kids no I didn't get it but
didn't get the jab either no yeah no I didn't but I didn't get it first time around I was like this
is crazy there was two days when I went to the because I was trying to get it and there's which
sounds horrible but I was not get it I just wanted to get over it like my kids got over it so fast
like my one daughter was one day she had kind of a headache and she tested for COVID she thought it
was hilarious she started laughing you know she's like oh my god I've got it but we had already told
them it's not dangerous for kids don't worry about it at all you know because there was a lot of kids
that were talking about getting vaccinated I'm like you are not getting none for them I was like no
way like it's not I'll do it if I have to work but what did you say no way like what what did you
think about it that you didn't even want your child to get it just totally unnecessary so no need to
risk it totally unnecessary they got COVID they got over it like that before the vaccine before the
vaccine but this is before the vaccine so after that I was like there's no way because there was
pressure from their friends to get vaccinated I was like do you're not getting vaccinated you have
seven times better immunity than someone who gets vaccinated which is proof and this is just
antibodies right which and you enlightened me in your book to the fact that there's cellular
immunity that's different than just antibodies anybody says one type of immunity to things right
that's right so uh it's that th2 slant that we were talking for me if with my kids it's like
they're vaccinated but we did it on a delayed schedule because that's what my doctor recommended
and we had a really good pediatrician and it worked out great they're fine but I was a little worried
I was I thought it was quack like to be worried like this is science like that what that what
vaccines could do to the kids you're the regular ones absolutely and the schedule the way they
wanted to just bang them up like real quick and with weird ones like the hepatitis B one that one
was like when I hear that I'm like what are you talking about you're going to give a kid for
a sexually transmitted disease a vaccine when they're a baby a one day old baby that's crazy
and also is there immune system even working right I mean will it even accept this and turn it into
an antibody like have you approve that like you're just jabbing kids and that child the infant will
make antibody and that's all they ever have to prove what they don't ever want to prove is that
when when you give this like say your child had gotten a COVID vaccine there's something called
original antigenic sin they changed the term to linked up atop suppression it happens with flu
shots it happens with lots of different vaccines is that if you program your body to attack you know
the strain of vaccine that you're a virus rather that you are injecting against and then a different
strain comes along it actually has negative efficacy you're one that's more likely to succumb
to terrible problems from the infection than because of your vaccine rather than actually
protecting you and that's been a well-known look Anthony Fauci writes about it morons and
Fauci wrote a paper basically admitting everything I think it was in 2023 or 2024 about these
shots and he said the COVID shots are exactly the same as the flu shots despite that despite
Fauci and morons talking about how these shots would never have been licensed if they were held
to the same standards of DPT et cetera et cetera that they don't provide lung immunity the only
provide blood immunity negative efficacy their their conclusion at the end of it is that we must
make better vaccines more effective vaccines to add to the already existing vaccine program it's
not that we shouldn't do this it's not that we should pull this off the market that's always the
logic again you they're not they never will admit to any problem with vaccines take it off the
market it's always adding to it not removing a vaccine at okay you think it was bad let's start
six months now six month old babies with parents that are just like you back in the day going okay
if you really think it's necessary because oh granny doesn't want to catch COVID we're gonna do
it yeah that was the logic what worry about granny but you know this is the great parenting
declaration right where those guys were like why don't we take the people that are vulnerable
and isolate them and treat them and and care for them and not worry so much about everybody else
and not shut society down because it's gonna have profound impacts and they were called kooks
and that's what's crazy it's like during the the the the the censorship was so rampant
that prominent scientists and physicians were removed from the social conversation because they
disagreed that's always been the case though that's always been it's just but what it's
happening on social media and it's so transparent these people getting removed from twitter you
like this is wild this this is so great that you find out that the government's involved
and the government contacted them and asked them to take things down you're like what are you what do
you say it like what this is nuts medical papers were retracted I mean there's this one guy named
Pradhan Pradhan who he showed that there is a GP 120 protein on the spike and he said it was
an uncanny similarity to the GP 120 and HIV and that there was no way that that would have come
out of nowhere and showed up in the 2019 COVID epidemic and he showed genetically how that just
couldn't possibly happen a flurry of emails went through the CDC and to NIAD and to Fauci and
within six days of that paper being a pre-print it was removed six days and what we've got we've got
access from the Freedom of Information Act to some of those emails are heavily redacted
but that was the that was the series of events that happened with that because any doubts whether
or not well-founded all the things you said about the COVID vaccine I'm sure are correct and true
but isn't it also different than the vaccine that they used in the test yes the vaccine that was
produced for the general public I believe at least when it comes to Pfizer they used magnetic
beads for purification which was totally different to what they did for the one they gave to us
and they produced it using I can't remember exactly how they produced it but they didn't use
plasmids and they didn't use you know all the all the different components that were given to us
I have a slide on that somewhere that I could show you about there were two aspects of the test
vaccine that were very different to the it was both the production how they produced it and how
quote purified it and what's the significance of the differences like did they do it
oh well there was no they just didn't have the plasmid they wouldn't have had the lipo polysaccharide
with the DNA from the from the E. coli that was in there that they told would never get past
our deltoid muscle and would be disintegrated well lipo polysaccharide actually is a transit protein
that can bring everything right through through your cells into your our cells are made of it's like
a lipid on the outside so that was the whole purpose was to shuttle this into your cells not only
that but the the the vaccine produced that the the plasmid part of the vaccine that's injected into
you the messenger RNA has a substitution for something called uridine they call it pseudo-uridine
and pseudo-uridine was put in there because they didn't want the immune system to destroy the
vaccine too quickly they wanted it to really be able to take hold of your body so you could have
a strong response well that's one of the reasons why vaccinated people had such you know horrible
a time with actual coronavirus when it did come and one of the reasons why you didn't even maybe
you were exposed and you don't you don't you don't know if you've had an antibody level tested
but again that's another long history thing is people who don't get sick while everyone else is
have been have been accused of witchcraft and sorcerers in the past and sometimes hunted down and
killed you know in the times of smallpox the groups of people that were into cleanliness and
that was a real problem for them I did do nasal swabs to see if I had any any antibodies I did do
that I didn't well that won't tell you antibodies that just that's a PCR that would be your PCR
test or your rapid which one did you do the one that the rapid the rapid antigen test but
that's only going to tell you if you've got active in your nose what you want to know is if you're
immune system again there's a good use for antibodies sometimes it's not to see it's not not
not the end all be all in terms of your immunity but it will show that you have had an experience
inside of your body with COVID and so who's bizarre to me was that there was this there's this
narrative that you were going to get it no matter what and and this will stop it from you getting it
yeah well was this is before the vaccine was even around there was this there's this talk that
there's no way to not get it like if it's around you it's so contagious you're going to get it
and that's why I was shocked that I didn't get it with my whole family got it like I said I
didn't isolate it all I did on purpose yeah and I had two days in the gym where I was sluggish
and so I was like I feel kind of tired today but a weird tire so I'm just going to go through
the motions I just like really light work out and the next day I felt the same thing like yeah
another light work out let's just take it easy no need to push it just got to break a little sweat
never stressed myself and then the next day I felt great I felt 100 like I started working I was
like oh I feel good and then I was fine I was like okay I guess I didn't get it and then everyone
of my family recovered and then I went from there to a couple months later I was doing this gig
in Florida and I was up with my friend John Showman who's a pool he makes pool cues shout out to
John good friend of mine and we were playing pool till like five o'clock in the morning and I have
like five margaritas and we're having a good old time and laughing a lot and then that night I was
like oh I don't feel so good but it was alcohol and no sleep and playing pool and you know and big
shows giant arenas and flying on jets and being tired all the time you know that's what it was
and then I got sick but even then it was like a couple days how was that how close was that to
the time you just said you felt a little tired in the gym that day few months okay a few months
yeah it was a few months because by that time the vaccine had been out and this was I guess the delta
which was everybody was like this is not bad one the delta's not bad one you're supposed to be
fearful you know yeah it was it was a shocking time for me because before that I never would have
guessed in a million years that I would be even questioning other vaccines I would have never
guessed that I would have told you that vaccines are one of the most important inventions in human
history and it saved us from polio it saved us from smallpox I would have been that guy
ranting off all those statistics I would have told you that but then I read your book
I've read sorry sorry I read Robert F Kennedy's book I read your book and I started reading
turtles all the way down which also the which is really interesting because they wrote another book
called turtles all the way down and someone else published it that has almost the identical cover
and that book is a pro vaccine book like they literally high jet they're like what do we do
well this is what we do we fucking confuse a shit out of people make one with the exact same cover
exact same cover exact same name wow and they made it a pro vaccine book it's kind of wild I
mean it's really kind of ingenious like what a great way to like flood the market with bullshit
and the RFK junior book was bananas I mean I the people had told me to read it and my initial
thought yes my initial thought was that's that guy that's like that anti-vaccine cook that's
what I thought and I apologize to him for that when when I talked to him on the podcast I said to
him I said I seek I succumbed like everybody else did to that the casual narrative was the
casual narrative oh that RFK guys are cook talks weird got a weird voice ruining the world's
immunity well I had the same thing like you know when I was first waking up I had a friend who had
unvaccinated kids they were part of a stiner school and they were like mutant freaks to me because
they'd never been on the antibiotic they were like bright and happy and interactive and talented
and at one point one of them was playing with a hammer and nail and I said to her mother I was like
you got to be careful because she doesn't have a tetanus vaccine and someone in the room said
well Suzanne what do you know about tetanus and like in my head I'm a full-fledged doctor at this
point I thought I don't know anything and outside I said I know you don't want to get it and I know
it'll cause lock jaw and then I started reading about tetanus and I had to go back and you know
kind of apologize and then I did a big video I have a big video out on tetanus and the actual truth
about the tetanus vaccines and actual tetanus which you know that's even harder for most people
like most people who don't want to vaccinate their kids will vaccinate for tetanus if they
get a single shot and second only to polio everybody's got their two vaccines that they're
their two diseases they're afraid of for the kid that makes them feel like they're at least doing
something well the polio one always gets thrown in my face because they take it all all the time
about polio yeah and I just go I don't have the time to do this thank you
I just to explain to someone the whole DDT connection and the fact that livestock was getting polio
like this is the thing like polio dogs don't get polio they don't get human derived polio
it doesn't cross species but they were getting paralytic polio symptoms because they were
getting poisoned by DDT right that was a big part of the whole thing that was very confusing
well they started killing dogs you know in in New York in that incident so I told you about
where the the vaccine the gain of function strain escaped people were throwing their cats out the
windows some 20,000 cats in New York City were killed during that time because they there was a
belief that cats spread the disease oh my god Jesus Christ that's so crazy and it was all a mutant
man-made virus the man-made virus thing is wound up wound up wound up by it was a basically a
natural virus that got kind of wound up by so man-made to the final form yeah that that's just
crazy that that's a thing that we do because if this gain of function research was so important
wouldn't you have a cure like ready like you've been studying this for so long but didn't they
but it didn't didn't really cure it right you know I mean wouldn't you have something that like
stops it dead and it's trying to cure it look I was living in a country where the government said
there's no cure for COVID there's no treatment for it and there is no prevention for it except
a vaccine and lo and behold we found out that there was a contract between the government and the
pharmaceutical industry to have the emergency use of the vaccine trial on on the population
only under the condition that there's no other treatment available and that's why the treatments
were shut down right yeah because emergency use there has to be no other treatment available if
you have Ivermectin or if you have zinc and all the other things that we use with success
you know there were so many people that I treated that should have been dead I gave COVID to a
95-year-old woman who had chronic lung disease called bronchi actuses she should have been the
low-hanging fruit I was starting to feel a little bit unhappy one day really just sluggish like you
mentioned and when I was done seeing I should go I just want to give you a hug and she can move
her and I was going oh no and after about three days I was like I've definitely got it I tested and I
I rang her daughter and I said I've got to tell you you know I was exposed Margie was exposed
to blah blah blah and she's like yeah mom's not feeling so good right now um and then two weeks
later I thought I've got to call back again I've got to make sure this lady's okay she's oh no
mom's out at the hairdresser getting her hair done two weeks later I still wasn't recovered two
weeks later she's out getting her hair done she's probably used to I don't know she can't
remember that detail but there was my senior partner had leukemia he should have been absolute
absolutely dead well not on my watch he wasn't going to be dead so he survived the entire thing
and died like two years later if something else so yeah the most shocking aspect of getting attacked
and like all the CNN stuff to me was that no one had any interest in why I recovered so quickly
because if this is supposed to be this death sentence and there's no treatment and then
I'm a guy in my 50s and I got over it quick and then no one cared at all about that all they
wanted to do is mock this idea that I was taking veterinary medicine right which I wasn't but it
was just the fact that they used that term horse dewormer on every TV show on it like wow this is
it's wild to watch the machine it's uniquely wild when it's coming after you and you know like
but this is like such a dumb checker's play I'm like this is so stupid I'm still doing my
podcast you fucking idiots and like everyone's gonna know that you put a green filter over my face
I'm gonna show everybody that you think you're just gonna get away with that no you're gonna like
lose all of your credibility idiots it was just so fascinating to watch like this distorted
understanding of like what America is willing to believe or the world is willing to believe like
you're only preaching to the converted the super hardcore closed-minded converted people
everyone else knows you guys are a joke now and that's the good part of getting through COVID
the good part of this enormous gas lighting experience that we all just went through where
people are finally after four years apologizing to friends you know for calling them a plague
you know like literally they got down to that where friends couldn't be friends with people
anymore because they weren't vaccinated and people are kind of like realizing like oh my god
not only did I get COVID more than anybody else because I got three shots like I had a friend
telling this he goes I got COVID more than everyone I know and I had all three shots he's like
I got COVID eight fucking times and we're like how many times did you get it and everybody that got
it naturally it was like I got it once maybe I got it I got it twice but the second time I got
it was literally a sniffy nose just literally a and I was joking because we used to test everyone
including the the guests everyone it came here we tested for COVID and I was joking I'm like maybe
this is it maybe I got it again and she's like you actually got it I was like no way this is COVID
and it never got worse it stopped right there it was that was it one day one day of a sniffly nose
and then a couple days later I said all right let's try and get tested again see if we can still
do another podcast and that was good but I had to cancel out to have a healthy immune system
but the fact that that's the thing it's like there's real science behind all the things you talk
about in your book in terms of like the the nutritional aspects of healthy foods being an important
factor in your immune system healthy we were talking about juices and vegetable juices and all
the different times that it's helped people overcome certain diseases and vitamin A and cod liver
oil which also has vitamin A which was always prescribed to people that were sick like all these
things are this is real science like there's real science and nutritional supplementation and the
effects that it has on the immune system and there's a real science in nutritional deficiencies and
what a negative impact it has this is all real and if they truly cared about you they would be
telling you about that as a primary way of defending your body against disease and against all sorts
of things that could go wrong all sorts of things like get fit eat healthy and you're above everything
take supplements you're above everything like you're in the top one percent of people that are
going to do great in life when it comes to getting sick just that because most people don't do that
so you have like what percentage of people like really eat healthy and really try to exercise
on a regular basis is it even 10 is it even 10 percent of us depends I get maybe what state you
live in let's just let's just have a guess nationwide and see if there's a chart see if there's a
statistic let's guess what percentage of people eat healthy take vitamins and exercise regularly
I say 10 percent what do you think yeah it could be because you still got your teenagers and
your young you college students that are in sports and things like that a lot of older people
are yeah but a lot of people like you know even though they have a hard job they still realize like
I got to go to the gym for work and just just get it in because if I don't I want to have an
energy I'm better off this way I know it sucks but just do it there's like people in it that have
enough discipline to do that so I would give it I think it's one out of 10 that's what I think
what do we got Jamie yeah it's a little bit impossible what about AI run that shit through
Chad you do well I'm just you get how are you gonna get the answers my point not like let's see
what you got Americans honestly answer the question and a poll that they're you know well let's ask
Chad GP just for a good I'm just my point to Chad GPT has to find the answer somewhere right but
let's see what she says well okay let's just for funsies let's just say I know right out of the gate
the answer is that 86 percent people take vitamins and supplements which is four and five
American adults is that real that's good if that's true that's really good I wouldn't think that's
true though I don't buy that that's what I'm trying to say yeah I don't buy that that's that's
written by a supplement company yeah and what supplements and how you know sometimes you can
overdo you do a hair mineral analysis on people and sometimes you find things that are you know
pretty shocking in terms of that came from supplements you know you you you can overdo it with
even selenium sure you can end up with big problem so there's also a problem with cross contamination
we want things that we found out when we were selling alpha brain is that in the beginning when
we would hire a lab to make the formula for us like so you you have like a list of ingredients
and then they put together this thing which is a new tropic that we'd find stuff in there that we
didn't have in there and it was from their bins so they didn't clean their bins so it's like
why has vitamin B12 in this like why is this in that why is that and it's just because that's the
same factor manufacturing place where they make all kinds of stuff creatine and okay likely less
than 10% okay if you're talking about people consistently do all three it drops significantly
less than 10% maybe in closer to 3 to 5% depending on how strict your definition of healthy is
yeah that's so that's what I was that was a good guess we're talking about adults here presumably
but you know one of the facts is that the foundation that your immune system is is created and
developed in is probably if not as more important than that and that is being born the vaginal
birth versus the C-section not putting down people have had C-section I'm just saying the science
the science shows that there is a distinct difference in C-section babies immune systems versus
non-C-section there's a distinct difference in breastfed babies versus non breastfed and there's
a distinct difference in babies whose mothers have a healthy diet in breastfeed versus mothers who
don't have a healthy diet in breastfeed so that foundation actually makes your gut grow normally
which is a large part of your immune system it colonizes your gut because the bacteria from your
mother's gut goes into your gut goes in from her gut through her lymph system into her breasts and
then to your gut and so all that foundational stuff is something not to be ignored because it's
going to make you deal with diseases better and if you have to get vaccinated it's going to make
you deal with vaccines better even as a child not that I'm in favor of that but I'm just saying if
you want to set things up as you know solidly as possible to be able to take that insult the
problem is we don't know 20 30 40 years later what the associations are between you know bone
diseases skin diseases cancers autoimmune diseases we have some clues I have some clues that nobody
wants to look at but we've got this long-term problem that nobody looks at long-term effects of
lifestyle of vaccination of even sp 40 there was one study that started tracking a thousand sp 40
people that they knew were infected with sp 40 looking for diseases later in life and they
stopped it after 19 years again axed when they still had over 700 people left in the study because
they said too much time had gone by well the fact of the matter is that's when the study should have
started 17 to 20 years later is when they still just started looking at that point not one year two
years but you know most vaccine trials and drug trials they don't they don't vaccine trials it's
like two weeks is a almost a miracle for someone to follow out that long forget about looking
months or years later doesn't happen when you first decided to write this book how much
apprehension did you have zero zero you were just fully convicted to get this idea out well you
know it was a bit of a process if you want to know it yeah sure yeah so what first happened is
I kept getting challenged while I was I stayed on for two years as an nephrologist in my hospital
so I wasn't kicked out I left because like my soul just couldn't hang out there anymore and
so during that time even though I was kind of ostracized behind my back everybody still respected
me as a nephrologist but I still had to go and in that in that time I started doing public
appearances like I went on the Gary Null show and started doing things like that just talking
about smallpox and polio because those were my focus because everyone's saying what about
smallpox what about polio and then when I started finding out I just I became obsessed with it
it was so interesting so I was morbidly fascinated by the whole thing and about how everything I found
was absolutely contrary to what the mainstream dogma is and what I had was a mountain you know
pile high to the ceiling and they had sound bites they had nothing to fight back with me on nothing
so this guy named Roman Bisterianic heard me on the radio show and he he rung my office and after
his third call I was like I guess I better call this guy back and and he had this idea for a book
and he had done all the charts and the graphics and started writing the narrative around that of
what the historical documents showed and then I came in as kind of the medical person that was
obsessed with polio and smallpox and happened to know quite a bit about pertussis so we started
writing the book together and there's probably about there's got to be if you were to take a full-time
job 20 years at least 20 years but for me it was condensed because I became obsessed after I quit
my job all I did I basically had no money I lived in a tent with a pop-up camper that was my office
and I was like crazy Ted Kaczynski obsessed with polio my tent and so no I didn't have apprehension
I was like this information it's been so that the US polio surveillance unit charts were supposed
to be available in libraries low and behold every library I went to to find them I was told
they're not here there's only one library the AMA library and you have to have special high security
clearance to look at them well I won't say how but I got a hold of them and what those documents
show is that it wasn't just cutter laboratories that had a problem with live polio it wasn't just
why if all the vaccine come we didn't talk about this but all the vaccine companies had a problem
with live virus and they're injectable vaccines during salks year so 1954 1955 up to 1959
they all were producing vaccine with live virus in it because salk wouldn't listen to the scientist
the broad who were saying his inactivation curve was where the sun doesn't shine so that beginning
of that and just tracking all that down and tracking asking the questions that you asked where
do polio go or you know what was really causing the paralysis why don't we see it today like I had
to answer all those questions and every question I answered it was so satisfying that I just wanted
to go on to the next question and so there was never any hesitation because I just actually I was
so single-minded that I didn't think about you know the the threats that could happen as a result
of that and it was until the after the book was out that the threats happened and I'm still here
and look I figure if anybody wants to do me and now the timing is really bad because this pretty
much out there now it's been out there for a while the Jonas Salk thing was also wild I thought
Jonas Salk was this genius that created this incredible virus to save humanity yeah so did I
so many of our childhood fables turned out not to be true but that was a big one and it's still
hard for a lot of people to believe but I just think it's like anything like if you're open to
different information and I always say look I am I may make I can make mistakes I'm not
infallible someone someone has actually found the mistake in the book actually went incorrect it
like that's the difference between me and these other people is that if I made a mistake I want
to know about it and I will go and make it right and I will publicly admit that I made a mistake
but I will say that 99.9% of what in this book what's in this book is true factual and provable
and because I've done the research but it's a hard thing to do what doctors going to quit their
job I was lucky I didn't have kids I didn't have you know medical royalty ancestors who would have
been disappointed in me I came from nothing I wasn't afraid to go back to nothing and so that's
why I was willing to live in a tent until this thing was done and published in 2013 so how long did
it take you I started working on it Roman had been working on it for years he had been going to
libraries because his kids got hit hard by an ex-wife who who jab them he didn't know about it and
they got really sick and then he started looking at old graphs and going oh that doesn't make sense
so he got obsessed in his own way with the numbers he's the numbers guy and so he'd been working
on it and then the two of us together worked on it probably from 2009 to 2013 and then it was
published in 2013 we couldn't find a publisher even the alternative publishers didn't want anything
to do with it so we self-published and then after it was successful guess who wanted to publish
our book and I was like nope sorry we're gonna carry on the way we are oh but you're gonna get
such more credibility it's like unlikely that's funny we did okay if you give us money you'll get
credibility let us take a part of your successful business that you worked on for five years or four
years look if you one dollar a book that would be sweet yeah great deal and then I'll have a
prestige behind my name yeah I've been published by a real company one was the last time you looked
at a book and said let me check who published this exactly maybe make sure somebody recommended
this book published it's all lies never heard of this publisher this is outrageous what's that
there for business science oh jock valet okay jock valet is probably the most interesting UFO researcher
whatever ever talked to he's the guy that was you remember the French scientist you might
be close encounters of the third kind did you see that movie the long time ago long time ago
do you remember there's a French scientist on the grounds courting any with with the army
and explaining to everybody what's going on okay that French scientist is modeled after this guy
this guy's been following UFO since like the fifties of the sixties do you say the fifties
like a long time he's an older gentleman but he's fascinating okay and he's very rational
when he talks about it it's like he is very objective in what's nonsense and what's true
and what we can't explain it's it's a fascinating subject yeah i think similar threads would run
through his experience definitely oh i'm sure yeah well it's for the longest time it was a ridiculed
subject not it didn't have the same societal impact as being a vaccine skeptic or a vat an
anti-vaxer right like by with that pejorative they've done an incredible job of scaring people
into just falling in line because if you question it and someone said oh did you know he's an
anti-vaxer right that's enough that's it that's all you need here and you're going to get the after
this podcast and i've already got you're going to get it big time i've gotten it already you know
start picking apart my facts and they want to come on and dismantle this is what always happens i
come in first i tell my story and then they bring in the experts who are able to take without me
being in the room of course because i can't be able to defend myself and then let the public
believe that everything i said was just one big sack of lies well they'll definitely be the
usual suspects that'll be doing that but has anyone ever tried to sit down with you and have a
conversation publicly about this and refute it not that i can recall no one's offered
yeah i have to say i'm not that interested in doing that because i just feel like
you know debate is it's an actual skill to be a debater people people study debate and people
get really good at it i'm i'm not a debater like i put if somebody wanted to debate me in writing
i would be happy to do that because then i could sit there and take my time you know go through
the the references that i needed rather than having to you know right that makes sense
you know have to be ready hits you know at me without having a shield right and there's an anxiety
aspect to that and like you know there's a lot of adrenaline and emotions and yeah it's a skill
but i would do it only if we had a topic that was you know basically agreed upon beforehand that
we could both upskill on and use what we know as as at the bait point but it usually just becomes
character assassination it does yeah it does it's super unfortunate and it's really transparent
when it's something about a serious object like why do you have to attack someone's who they are
make make it ridicule them instead of just refuting the facts or or laying out your case
it just doesn't make sense that anybody who's right would do that that's not what you do when
you're right that's what you do when you're trying to ridicule people and you're usually trying
to ridicule people because you need an edge you know it's like a bully they're like if you see
fighters like like a like a UFC fighter in his prime like Anderson so was one of the greatest of
all time if someone like god in his face and tried to intimidate him it would be kind of hilarious
because he was the best fighter in the world right so he wouldn't even have to do it back he could
just smile at you and that's sort of the same here when you're ridiculing someone specific like right
off the bat a bunch of you know add hominem about that person you're trying to diminish that person
to set up your argument as being superior because you have a superior intellect and you're doing
that because you don't feel like you're on level playing fields and so you want to try to do something
to push them off make fun of them and some sort of instead of just like laying out your version
of what reality is lay out your version if you're so strong if you're so correct it should be super
easy to do well just like in sports it's the same here it's like cheating is for losers you know
if you're a winner you're not you don't have to cheat and yeah and that's the same with them like if
their product is so wonderful that everybody needs it so badly then why is there such is they
what they say is that we're too stupid to understand how they're saving our lives and how they
this is one of the big arguments that we really ought to touch on is that they say that our lifespan
has improved as a result of medical interventions when what we show in here what other scientists have
shown is that it's about 3.5 percent of the contribution from medicine goes into our extended
lifespan 3.5 percent based on antibiotics vaccines etc the rest of it was all about the revolution
the health revolution the clean water the shelter the electricity the child labor laws you know
ending so you know the magic of medicine is not what people think and it really traps it really
traps a lot of people like I I think there's a value to to the medical field in terms of surgery
and certain drugs and if you have an organ failure like absolutely but why not like my
Hippocratic oath said that I should consult you know any consultant that will help my patient
and keep the well-being of my patient stable well to me that includes you know using every therapy
that is as the most benign therapies possible first the ones that work along with the blueprint
of your human body that go along with the the theory of health rather than pounding down disease
you're always going to get a better result that way assuming you've got time and you know you
haven't waited till the last minute we certainly will get a better result if you do get the disease
that way like the idea that you could just ignore everything but of medication is so silly
and it doesn't the only reason why you would do that is if that's the only way you made your money
and that's really especially if you're in the vaccine business and you're
you have an enormous ad budget and you're sponsoring all the television networks
well that's the big thing and the other thing is people trust what they see on the television
you know CNN I can see an end with my go-to thing for the long time yeah
and now I look at it and I think oh my goodness you know what cracked it for me is when
when they when they publicly villainized Andy Wakefield and I actually knew the story behind
Andy Wakefield at the time the story behind him is that you know he was he was a doctor you'll hear
he was publicly shamed his license was removed he he published an article about what what he
called toxic nodular enturo colitis in children with autism he was a gastroenterologist a very
high-level very well-respected decorated gastroenterologist and he published this paper which remained
in a journal for 12 years and all it said at the end was further research needs to be done in
order to see if there is any real connection between the MMR vaccine autism and toxic
nodular enturo colitis these kids suffer with horrible bowel disease it's not just brain disease
and so after he was about to publish another paper showing that in this certain type of monkeys
that were vaccinated against hepatitis B lost a lot of their reflexes and had problems
and was on the eve of the publication of that paper that his original paper was revoked
and ever since then he has been the poster child for vaccine nonsense for anti-vax crazy people
and in fact every time I've done anything his name funny that I brought his name up I love him
he's a great guy but his name would always come up well you're a friend of Andy Wakefield or
Andy Wakefield because autism and vaccines has been debunked because Andy Wakefield lied and he
didn't lie all he said is I did biopsies I saw this and this is possibly a connection and since
then other scientists have come in done the same thing biopsies then they looked at whether the
vaccine virus was in that biopsy and it was it wasn't a wild virus was the vaccine virus in that
area not the surrounding area so there is a relationship between gut disease MMR vaccine retained
virus that hasn't been processed properly because it didn't come into your body properly
and disease brain disease so that's a fact but CNN did a hit job on Andy Wakefield and I remember
going huh well what's going on here because I know I know what happened with that whole situation
now CNN is saying this and that was kind of when you know the windscreen cracked for me and I just
had to start questioning anything and then you've got you know the doctors that go on there there
a couple doctors I think you interviewed one of them didn't you? Sanjay Gupta yeah you know there
was a guy before him and some of the stuff he said was pretty unbelievable but that's what the
public is going to hear you know your best chances of dealing with this is to just get the vaccine
you don't want to get shingles get that vaccine never mind the whole other truth around that because
like you say it's the advertisers but it's bigger than that does the shingles vaccine work?
well what do you think about giving yourself a vaccine for something you already have
like you think about it like chickenpox is a disease that we all got as kids you got it as a kid
probably like you're kind of superhuman though you didn't get COVID I got it eventually yeah
so I got you got it eventually they broke you down but I got chickenpox really bad and then
I got chickenpox and I was a kid yeah there you go so back in the old days we would all get chicken
pox and then we'd be exposed to other kids that had chickenpox we'd go over kids houses if they
had chickenpox yeah people do they still do that I didn't have to I got it somehow I don't know
how I got it probably for my brother and so you have this dormant this this virus lays dormant
in your body until your immune system breaks down so but part of it is not just your immune system
break that's the fact that all these kids are now vaccinated and the circulation of the disease
see some vaccines work in terms of they stop the circulation of the disease
but add a detriment to us so it's been a detriment for measles and it's been a detriment for chickenpox
so chickenpox we used to get continues you didn't have adults didn't get shingles it was very
rare for adults to get shingles before the chickenpox vaccine came out extremely rare but since then
rate of shingles and adults and children has skyrocketed because we're no longer getting our
boosters being exposed to the circulating microbes so now the solution to that is to give adults
like four times the the dose of the childhood chickenpox in an injectable vaccine against
something that they already have and so the theory is that you're going to ramp up your antibodies
and then you're going to be able to do battle if your if your viruses come out again the only
problem with that is that the problems is the immune system if you get AIDS or you're on chemotherapy
you chances that happening are really high and uh yeah does the vaccine work or not I don't know
I just don't think it's just to me just a completely strange concept to inject myself with
something that I already have along with all the other excipients and compounds to go in a vaccine
that nobody wants to talk about either so can you explain how a vaccine is manufactured like how
could they not know all the different stuff that's in it like who like let's let's let's let's talk
about like how the SV40 got in there so to you need something alive you need some sort some
sort of tissue from a living creature in order to grow these things well in terms of the COVID
vaccine you just needed to pile crap actually because it's made on e coli cells and that's where
you find e coli so with a lot of the other vaccines you do need living like for for tetanus you need
rotten meat okay that's how the tetanus vaccines made with rotten meat you were talking about
tetanus earlier and you kind of glossed over it but you didn't finish up you were saying that
that tetanus itself you started like googling and like reading about tetanus itself yeah yeah
have a big wake up call with tetanus so you know what we see if if anyone's worried about tetanus
what we're shown is a picture of a soldier from like the 1800s with his what he's naked and his
our his back is arch if you just google tetanus right now and you look for images you'll get this
image and so that's what we're told will happen if we get tetanus it's a sure thing you're just
gonna get tetanus you're gonna die well the fact of the matter is that when I started doing my deep
dive in world war one look it was fought in the trenches with horses that's where you get tetanus
from ruminant animals lives in their gut and it goes in the soil and it's just a spore doesn't
do anything until it gets into an area that doesn't have oxygen so you get a cut you get a surgery
to close you up real nice without cleaning it out properly and you're a setup for tetanus which
transform from a spore to a different kind of a micro and start releasing a toxin that can
it first starts as numb numbness usually in that limb it's the extreme case is in that soldier
who would have been malnourished stressed out probably vaccinated for smallpox before he hit the
fields and exposed to enormous amounts of of tetanus probably gunshot wound or a slice
somewhere and then sewn up so yeah his nervous system could have had a real big dose of toxin
and nobody did anything about it that's the worst case scenario you don't want that to happen
but in today's today i've treated tetanus let's just put it that way i've treated several cases
of tetanus some one of the cases was neurologically diagnosed tetanus so tetanus is treatable
you can get on it early rabbit rabbit studies have shown that if you give vitamin C if you have a good
high vitamin C level before you put glass with tetanus spores on it inside the skin of a rabbit
that you can prevent the tetanus from happening even if you give the vitamin C at the time of the
injury you can prevent it from happening if you give it after the event the death rate goes down
to you know very very low if not zero so vitamin C is a main factor but the biggest factor is
cleaning a wound and keeping the wound open if you think it's a dirty wound and not to close it
straight up which is why nails you say stepping on a nail is the classic because rust can kind of
hold the old spores inside of it you step on the nail you get inoculated and then you wait for
to heal over what you have to open that wound if that's going to happen but you know tetanus has
but there was a there was a there's a whole series of reports on instances where the cotton
that was made for menstrual pads for women postpartum was impregnated with tetanus and they
got horrible cases of tetanus just from using those menstrual pads so the hospital systems have
also been you know responsible the biggest thing is that being vaccinated for tetanus is not
necessarily security against not getting tetanus now my telling people not to go get vaccinated
or not no I'm not I'm just saying there's so much look every vaccine there's so much more to
the story that should be considered you can have different strains of tetanus and if you're living
on a field that has room in animals you will be whether you like it or not you're going to be
eating whatever is down in that field and you're going to be inoculated and have antibody and
probably some mediated immunity against it so you'll already have some immunity to that so worst
case scenarios you have no immunity you go get a dirty wound and you don't get any real
competent medical care for it yeah you can end up getting having a problem with tetanus whether
you're not going to have lock jaw and an arch back and die unlikely today for that to happen
but most tetanus that happens is delayed on set so the earlier your symptoms come on the
worst the tetanus is going to be if it comes on later generally the better you're going to do
treated with high doses of magnesium high doses of vitamin C local wound care that's the
best thing that you can do up to you if you want to go get jabbed for tetanus after you learn
everything about it everything's on my Odyssey channel by the way that's where all that because
I got canceled out of YouTube for talking about vitamin C for all of all things so everything's
now on Odyssey all my videos are on Odyssey and I do do one that's just on tetanus and again
medical reference after medical reference I don't make this stuff up I just report what I read
yeah it's crazy that they just kick you off YouTube for reporting studies yep yet you can have
like pornography and murder and all kinds of other stuff on there it's it's pretty horrifying some
of the things that flash across like I wish I can't unsee that now have you ever post your stuff
on X yes lots of stuff on X yeah so most of this stuff is available there well I got canceled
out of Twitter when it was Twitter and I could not make another account it's like they knew where
I was they they were able to even always use different phone numbers and different emails I could
not restore an account bigger IP yeah maybe that's what I used to I use VPN as well couldn't do it
really then I would get an account set up and then they would say you went against standards and
cancel it so anyway they must have put a cookie on your phone or something maybe try a new phone
I tried a computer too wow but I did finally get a get an account I was able to open an account
and get a blue check mark but I've only got look I don't have that many followers I'm going to
went from having over 95,000 to having nothing and now rebuild that's they love that they love
to let us build ourselves up and chop us down and make us rebuild what is your account we'll help you
out it's DR it's Dr. Suzanne H7 DR SUZ and NEH7 yeah and I own look I don't post my opinions about
different things in the world and dog and cat pictures like I post stuff about vaccines you know
I like I stay in lane as best as I can so for you was the COVID pandemic was that like a big wake-up
call for people to start reading your book we've we've had pretty good sales like Roman keeps
because he does all the accounting and he says we just have a good amount of steady sales
once in a while we'll see it like every time you mentioned the book we had a little blip on it
during COVID every time Bill Gates comes out and says something stupid we have a big surge in our
sales so they actually help us when they sit with their you know we're gonna if we've vaccinated
enough people we can help depopulates like okay and for whatever reason our book sales go up
when he starts talking about vaccine deniers and vaccine skeptics when whenever they started doing
that in the way the language that it would use was like when the president was saying our patients
is wearing thin we've been patient with you but our patients is wearing thin and the White House
prints this thing that if you're vaccinated you did your job but for those unvaccinated you're
looking looking forward to a what did they say a winter of a dark winter of death and disease
like what you know dark winter was a tabletop exercise do you know about tabletop exercises I do
but what is dark winter so dark winter was one you can explain tabletop exercise that involves small
pox well there are lots of them but Johns Hopkins does I have a whole PowerPoint on this too but
Johns Hopkins conducts a lot of them they they involve fictional scenarios where you know there
could be pandemics and terroristic depositions of toxins and chemicals and microbes that were
manipulated in a lab and then who in this in our society is going to respond and how they're
going to respond like the CDC and DARPA and the news outlets are always up utmost importance as
the news outlets and the messaging that goes to news outlets and these tabletop exercises but dark
winter was one that was a tabletop exercise after the World Trade Center is thing when we were
pointing our fingers at a rock and weapons of mass destruction and a Russian scientist that you
know had weaponized smallpox and brought it to Iraq which they never found by the way but because
of that that's why I was asked to get vaccinated for smallpox in 2003 was that dark winter
whole that dark winter thing that was going on thank god there were a few people on the CDC and
consultants old guys the old guys with integrity that like knew the deal from the old days we're
saying wait a minute smallpox is not easily transmitted so that's and that's a no-no so even if
there is a terroristic smallpox drop it's not going to be easily easily transmitted it's treatable
and the vaccine doesn't necessarily prevent it and so that was kind of one of the things that
stalled it all out but then they did the study on the Marines because they the part of the exercises
are we must do tests for the new vaccine they use the old vaccine the drive-axe and there were
lots of problems with those military people and then I was asked to sign a 63 page informed
consent basically saying that I understood all the problems that could happen to me that I didn't
have little kids in my life that I wasn't going to be able to spread it I would isolate after I
got the vaccine so they're ultra ultra careful about this one because they knew they were dealing
with something that could be get a very bad reputation reputation the reason they ultimately
canceled it is because any doubts whether or not well funded must not be allowed to exist because
if we were saying oh my gosh we have this terrible smallpox vaccine how did they do it back then we
have the same vaccine and people are getting really sick and dying and having cardio myopathies
that's a problem and so that's why the truth gets locked down over COVID we know luckily you
seen the athletes dropping dead you know about the cardiomyopathies and the pulmonary embolite and
on all that kind of thing nobody's talking about the stem cells that the newborn babies are born
without nobody's talking about the fact that there are now death dualists to deliver dead babies
like that wasn't even a thing before but I've got a friend that's a midwife who tells me that
they are now creating a new field which are midwives that only deliver dead babies into nothing else
they didn't need that before COVID was an absolute nightmare in terms of obstetrics gynecology
labor and delivery a lot of midwives that that got done and and because they didn't get vaccinated
they don't even want to go back now that they can go back because they don't want to have their
good reputations of 100% of you know normal births being dealing with what's being dealt with today
in terms of the birth problems that are happening because of the actual vaccine itself because
look if it causes problems and blood clots in our circulation what do you think it's going to do
to a placenta that is pretty much all blood vessel that's all it is it's like a big blood vessel
sandwich is what it is and there was no studies that showed that it was safe to give to pregnant
women but yet they were saying that well there's look every influenza vaccine package insert says
it's never been tested for carcinogenic genicity or muted genicity and pregnant women yet
it's recommended every year for every pregnant woman and every time they get pregnant or not
it's recommend the same with the pertussis vaccine give it to pregnant women never
mind that it changes the immune the immune reactivity of the infant nobody talks about these
things this is what I say when you know it's like the truth is so much more complicated than the
sound bite lie the sound bite lies what gets around the world three times science is settled
science is settled there's no debate needed because the likes of me are so crazy and you know
whacked out and you know when I'm trying to destroy the good the good order of the the general
public things like that blood is on your hands blood oh that's a good one I always love that one
yeah that's a fun one yeah yeah yeah yeah put see if you can pull up rational wiki and hum free
you'll enjoy this I want to see the image of the guy with tetanus did you find that
can I just see one I want to see what it looks like when you're locked it's an old painting
well the one I saw it was like hey I want so can I ask you when you've treated people that have
tetanus and didn't have the tetanus shot or did they get tetanus and they have the tetanus shot
the one that had the worst tetanus had Ted Lockjohn had the tetanus shot put in painting put
in artwork look at that dead guy but go up to that dead guy yeah right there that's not real
meaning it looks real it looks fake a shit does it does not to me bro it could be it could be but look
it he's he's clearly been in the hospital for a really long time probably got hospital acquired tetanus
okay you know right but that image right there what what makes you think that that's fake
yeah that is weird that part there looks it does look fake oh yeah it's probably a bunch of
Nazi tetanus but if you put in painting painting soldier tetanus that then it will come up
is that it right there it is first one right there very famous that's what's on the wikipedia page
as well so this is so that you don't want that to happen yeah if you do get tetanus and there
is no antibiotics this is surely what will happen to you now today how would you treat someone who
got tetanus all that there are antibiotics you know that you but mostly it's supportive care
until you know your therapy starts to work so some people end up if if it's not dealt to in time
you can end up ventilated but again that's it's a theoretical problem but if you get on it in time
that's not certainly not been my experience and so the ones that I've treated that haven't been
vaccinated have had the easiest mildest cases but so your point is I don't know I've not done a
large randomized controlled study but but what's really important here is what you're saying is that
even if you get the tetanus shot if you step on a nail like you could still get tetanus look
the tetanus one of the tetanus in order to make tetanus immune globuline which is another option
when say you have a cut and your magic tetanus shot doesn't work right away then you can get an
immune globuline injection that came from somebody who has had tetanus usually these are people who
have actually had tetanus not who have been back and one of the don't one of the donors that's in
the literature that I use is somebody who has had natural tetanus despite having several
several vaccines so no the tetanus vaccine is not a guarantee against severe tetanus
yeah that's right before you die they call it severe yeah but the set of calls to be caused by my
so this is the this is the kind of the dead baby equivalent um of you know that they use for tetanus
so this was a soldier I believe during a very long time ago and he was uh don't even show you
it was wound he's probably stepped on something it can happen not saying it can't but again
our parents given well-rounded information no they're not they're not told that there are actually
things you can do to prevent tetanus shouldn't they at least we told how to clean out a wound
right and not to let anybody sew it up and secondary healing is a thing like some people get open
heart surgery and because they get infections I've seen this happen they they just leave everything
open and let it fill in on its own you end up with a big scar but they're still alive because the
the infection was able to heal from the inside out or rather the wound was able to heal from the inside
out well you don't want to happen as a wound to heal from the outside because then you're locking
in dead tissue which is a perfect setup tetanus loves dead tissue which is why they use dead
rotten meat to grow the vaccine. What is it like to have your entire view of medical history
do a 180 like what it what does it like to be a practicing doctor and someone who never would
have imagined this until you faced these it's kind of exciting actually because during my medical
residency like towards the end of it I was like I just thought one day I'm not a healer I don't
I don't know how to heal anything I'm just prolonging people's lives treating their diseases with
drugs like I'm a glorified pharmaceutical technician I realized that one day and I was like I'm
not a surgeon I can't do surgery so I write prescriptions I do diagnoses and I write prescriptions
so I decided to go into a field where people really needed prescriptions like if you don't have
kidney function you're on dialysis like that's one of the glories of medicine like you can prolong
people's lives I really enjoyed that but then after I left completely and I started studying
real physiology beyond what I learned in medicine like I'm learning a lot of the stuff you're
learning too you know the new tropics and all that stuff that you talk about while I'm learning
about that that we're I love it actually it's exciting I've been liberated from from a prison
essentially from a stupid prison where your where my brain was locked down and I was told
what to do and how to do it and then watching the results it would be one thing of the results
were good okay but the results aren't good like you we treat symptoms we treat hypertension
hypertension is a symptom it's not a disease hypertension can come from lots of different things
that's just one case in point so I really love being able to now have the freedom to look at the
full human being and their physiology and look at them as an electromagnetic entity that has some
chemicals and and vitamins and help them direct their body back towards the blueprint that it
was designed upon and that's to me what real healing and real medicine is about it's not about
being anti-antibiotic anti this anti that it's like how about pro life how about we get your
you know you're going out working every day that's great because you know why you're getting your
blood and your lymph flowing and you're sweating you sweat you know the aluminum comes out in your
sweat toxic metals come out in your sweat you create salt levels in your blood that stimulates
your skin immune system which is a separate entity like I didn't know any of this when I was
of conventionally practicing doctor just even say like I wanted to detoxify mercury out of my
patients in order to lower their blood pressure and I was told that that was not allowed we're not
like well then I don't want to do this anymore because I know from a hair mineral analysis
and from a chelation test that that person is burdened with aluminum and mercury and I know that
those both of those things can raise blood pressure so why wouldn't we want to remove that the
same reason we're not allowed to say vaccines but you know what a multi-billion dollar industry blood
pressure treatment is and cholesterol treatment is oh no forget about it um yeah I mean I saw
malignant hypertension after happened after a tetanus shot an adult patient of mine and so that
was another one you know thing that woke me up and I was like gosh that's weird and then I you
look up you see there's other case reports and then you're told case reports don't mean anything
you need randomized controlled studies yeah so it's it's like there's frustration at every corner
but I love doing what I do now and and I love I love the fact look it was all it's all great like
I wouldn't change anything in my life just put it that way and I'm really glad I have the
background of conventional medicine but that's like background of conventional medicine is like
year one and really learning about healing and life it's just it's the very basics and and and
doctors still need to keep learning but what most conventional doctors are mandated to keep learning
but they can oh they're told where they can read to get their credits every year you can only get
your credits from reading this and answering the questions like a good little doggy every year
which I still have to do um but but beyond that when I have my own spare time you know like I've
learned ozone therapy I've learned how to use vitamin C I've learned how to look at the body
electromagnetically and use bio resonance and there's just so much stuff you can do that
really helps people and keeps them out of a whole bunch of trouble that they would have gotten
into if they went and took allergy medicines and got their tonsils out or kept on their blood
pressure medications and let the inflammation go wild in their body and didn't know anything about
how to dampen look most disease comes from inflammation you know cholesterol is trying to save you
it's not trying to kill you the cholesterol is a response to inflammation it's like your fever is
trying to save your life it's like everything in medicine is about dampening down the the symptoms
that are trying to save your life you know so it's like I'd look at it and I think I can't believe
I ever actually agreed upon that well it took a lot of courage to step out of line and speak
your mind and I'm really glad you did because I hope more will realize that this is what a doctor
is supposed to do and you're not supposed to be a spokesperson for an industry that's pretty
sociopathic you know which makes some you know great strides look there's a lot of amazing orthopedic
surgeons and eye surgeons and neurosurgeons there's a lot of amazing work being done by medicine
but then there's also the pharmaceutical drug company which when attached to that and to the money
people they want to make more money every time they can every quarter they want to have a bigger
quarter they want a bigger house they want a bigger jet and they just keep going and the way to get
money is to get you to take their stuff it's not to heal you the way they really make money is to
get events you that you're sick and if that wasn't the case we would have more medical freedom
than we have right right because we would have choices we would have options it wouldn't be told
what we have to do to protect the public you shouldn't be shamed for getting better from some
other way that wouldn't be a thing I know that wouldn't be a thing crazy isn't it yeah it's
pretty weird well thank you very much for for doing what you do and for writing that book because
it was it was a real eye opener for me you know I had no idea I had no idea the history of these
things I had no idea the correlations between like when the vaccine was induced and what when
the death rates had already dropped down I didn't know all that stuff until I read the book I do
not remember I don't remember somebody recommended it okay and you read it yeah cheers to you
well it's a page turner you know it's I listened to it in my car too and I listened to it in the
sauna it's one of those books that you kind of have to go over it a couple of times just to sort
of digest it and go wait a minute wait wait wait wait wait wait wait wait wait wait wait hold on
apple cider vinegar they were using to stop people from getting smallpox like what the fuck is that
how is that real like the doctors were saying that they were treating people with smallpox and they
didn't worry about getting it because they were consuming apple cider vinegar multiple times a day
it actually worked that's what the reports showed even today apple cider vinegar you know it's
had a big resurgence in terms of new you know keeping your gut pH nice and low so that you can
digest your food better which has downstream effects to everything but it's also a fermented
product you know it's it's got a lot of benefits not just that but even on the skin it's like
really great to put on chickenpox and probably smallpox as well but if I may just direct people to
dissolving allusions.com because if you just go to amazon you're not going to there's two different
versions of the book there's the original one that you read and then there's the 10th anniversary
version that has 200 extra pages and we delineate early on with the new what the new pages what the
new chapters are so you don't have to go read the old stuff if you don't want to what are the new
200 pages cover it covers tuberculosis it covers oh one of this one of the chapters I really love
it's it's toxic medicine of the past all the different crazy treatments that I was telling you
and then I added a whole bunch of the hooping cough because more information came out after 2013
so we added that in and then we published a second book which is all full of doctor quotes from
200 years ago because people say why are you the only one it's like well I'm actually not the only
one it's like back then this was what was recorded from doctors and public health officials which
is probably 1% of what actually was said and then we have hard to find vaccination tragedies
royal commission on vaccination timeline and then we have rare documents at the back
that has like the encyclopedia Britannica where they hired a very highly decorated well-known highly
respected doctor to write a chapter on smallpox and at the end when he did what I did and basically
looked at all the facts he decimated the the vaccine completely so that you can't really find
that very easily anymore so this one is called the companion book to dissolving illusions and then
but if you you can see all the versions and all we've been translated into eight languages where
about to be translated into Chinese but the best resource is dissolving illusions dot com and it
will show you what your options for purchase and where you can purchase the different books if you
want to you know an alternative press we have an alternative press for those people that don't want to
do amazon so yeah and all the different languages and the different versions are on there all right
thank you again thank you very much really appreciate you my pleasure all right bye everybody