It's Tuesday, April 8th, here's what's happening right now on CNN this morning.
I have great respect for China, but they can't do this.
President Trump threatens to escalate his trade war with China, issuing them an ultimatum
and a deadline.
The China does not appear to be backing down, plus our team will get to work tomorrow to
deport these heinous, violent foreign terrorists.
The White House can resume rapid deportations, but there's a catch, new rules from the
Supreme Court, also.
This is the highest I've seen the water in my lifetime.
The flooding danger is not over as deadly storms leave some communities under water.
And in three short years, we got the University of Florida's basketball program back where
it belongs, which is winning national championships.
The Gators' Trump, Florida rallies past Houston to win the title, how they pulled off a comeback
in the final seconds.
It's 6am here on the east coast, here's a live look at Cincinnati, where communities around
the Ohio River could still see some more flooding threat today.
Good morning, everybody, I'm Audit Cornish, I want to thank you for waking up with me.
And the question this morning, who will blink first?
Donald Trump is threatening even more tariffs on China.
The president says he will impose an additional 50 percent tariff tomorrow if China doesn't
call off their tariffs today and caught in the middle of this, you, the consumer, here
at home.
We are now working right now, we're being working two days a week, mean kind of slow,
there is no much work right now.
Economy, we're smaller port, we're going to feel it, drivers will work half a day instead
of a full day.
All right, so you heard there from a trucking company at the port of Oakland, that's where
they receive almost half of their shipments from China, and it's just one example of
how President Trump's tariffs are actually impacting people's lives, even before many
of them have gone into effect.
Some of the world's wealthiest businessmen are also making it clear that they're not
on board, Richard Branson calling the tariffs a colossal mistake.
Republican Megadoner Ken Lagonate says he doesn't understand the bleeping formula, and Bill
Ackman, another Trump backing billionaire, warning of a self-induced economic nuclear
winter.
President Elon Musk says he wants to see this, the U.S. and Europe may be moved to a relationship
with zero tariffs.
President Trump, however, is not flinching, nor is China.
This morning, a spokesperson for the Foreign Ministry accused the U.S. of economic bullying
and said that in a trade war quote, China will fight to the end.
We're trying to keep our prices right where they are for the time being, although again,
we reserve the right over the next month or two or three, as our paper goods start to
run out to see what tariffs are doing at that point, because those 30 percent tariffs
out of China and Vietnam are going to be high.
Okay, a sign that the market may be as resilient as the President hopes U.S. futures are pointing
up this morning.
Global markets also ticked up following Monday's major losses.
The group chat is here to discuss Jackie Kassinage, Washington Bureau Chief for the Boston
Globe, Chuck Rocha, Democratic Strategist, and former Senior Advisor to Bernie Sanders Presidential
campaigns, and Mike Dubkey, former White House Communications Director during President
Trump's first term.
Okay, Jackie, I want to start with you because obviously we are seeing a market that is so
desperate for anything that like little rumors actually sent things up and down yesterday.
What is it that we're hearing from the White House?
The White House is still projecting that this is something that's going to work, that
they just need patience, and frankly, you're seeing it reflected back at them on the
hill.
They've managed to kind of quash any effort to, at this point, to claw back some power
to Congress, Republicans who were starting to express some dissent have quieted down.
We'll see how long that lasts as the market continues to do with the market has been doing,
and Congress comes back, but certainly at this point, at least from their party, right
now everyone is staying in line.
But during that press conference on yesterday, you did have the President say, yeah, I might
do this, yeah, I might do that, we'll have to see, so the uncertainty still remains even
as they're saying they're being steadfast.
You know, this latest threat of 50% tariffs that's on top of last week's 34%, 34%, which
is itself on top of the existing 20%, I mean, basically if the President makes good on
all of these promises, Chinese goods would face an effective tariff of 104%, Chuck, how
long do you think people can, I don't know, experience this shift and go along with what
the President wants, because culturally, Americans are used to less expensive goods.
Yes, we've, I would say we've gotten addicted to cheap goods, and people made that economic
philosophy back in the day when Walmart was booming, folks decided that they wanted to buy
lots of cheap stuff from China, but let's talk about the American voter and not the billionaires,
because the American voter is really going to determine what happens here, because we
have a midterm election where they'll be heard in about 18 months, and a regular citizen
out there, he watches or she watches the stock market here there, but they don't understand
instability, buybacks, bonds, all the others.
If you're 66 and you're thinking about retiring, sure, you watch it every single day, but
regular folks, there's two things that really affect them politically.
One is when they get their 401k statement, they always look like I do to see if you've
made a little money or you've lost a little money, and over time, that becomes a problem
with the perception from that voter and the second thing, which we talked about a lot
on this program, which is why Donald Trump got elected, was the price of things, the affordability
of things.
Every time's eggs go up, our gas goes up, people feel that because they're buying them
every single week, and that's where the American public is, if this keeps driving up or drives
up prices at all, then I think you're going to see a repercussion from the American voter.
Mike Dupke, I want to bring you in, because there's that we've mentioned coffee, we've
talked to the truckers, another interesting data point, Nintendo had just announced its
new consoles, stay with me, the Switch Duo last week, and basically, as soon as it did
that, it had to halt US pre-orders because of Trump tariffs, 24% tariff on Japan basically
could make the device unaffordable for a lot of people.
This could touch people in a lot of different ways, beyond the arguments that the White
House is making.
Mike, do those moments matter or has the White House just made the argument so cleanly
that people see this as a way to bring back manufacturing?
So I'm going to answer this in two ways.
First of all, I'm going to agree with a lot of what Chuck just said, and this is going
to be a very happy, you know, cold, get along Tuesday here.
I think the American people, especially the 40% that aren't invested in the stock market
are looking at those prices every day, and we've seen a slight downturn in inflation,
we've seen a slight downturn in some prices.
So right now for the new base of the Trump administration, and frankly, the Republican
Party do a certain extent, is not revolting on this.
But let's get back to your original question about China.
I think China is the fight that the president wants.
If you look at the Nikkei average this morning, you see that it's rebounding because he's
negotiating with Japan.
With Europe, there's spent some movement.
I think the fight with China is what the president and the administration would like to focus
on, and that's what we're about to see.
So they're setting this up.
I don't think the communications have been great coming out of the White House.
It's been kind of all over the map, but I think it's starting to settle in in a place
that's a positive for Trump.
Okay, stay with me.
There's a lot going on.
Before we go, I want to play this one last cut from Peter Navarro, basically Trump's
trade advisor, making a promise, and I feel like these are the kinds of promises that
really should be on record.
Dow 50,000, I guarantee that, and I guarantee no recession, okay?
Why?
Because when we pass the biggest, broadest tax cut in history within a matter of months,
that's going to be a great stimulus.
There's not going to be any inflation.
You guys stay with us.
We're going to talk a lot more this hour about what's going on.
So how should Democrats respond to President Trump's policies that are reshaping America?
What's their path forward?
Senator Bernie Sanders is going to look to answer those questions in a CNN town hall that's
going to be posted by Anderson Cooper.
That's happening Wednesday at 9 p.m. Eastern right here on CNN.
And coming up on CNN this morning, parts of Appalachia still reeling from Hurricane
Helene, and now Doge is looking to decimate staffing at FEMA.
We're going to have Republican Congressman Chuck Edwards.
He represents one of the areas it hardest.
He's going to talk more about that.
Plus, the U.S. and Iran may be sitting down for talks on its nuclear program.
Can they come to a deal?
And historic rainfall, sending rivers, surging, and the flooding isn't over yet.
The water was up to my thigh, ice cold, and then as I stepped out, I almost failed because
the water was dragging me.
I'm Dr. Sanjay Gupta, host of the Chasing Life Podcast.
What we see is that people who sit on the ground, they're five key times get faster.
They're back, stop hurting.
That's Dr. Kelly Starratt, co-author of a really good book called Built to Move, to give
all of us busy people some of the simple tools to improve our range of motion, our posture,
decrease our pain, and yes, become more mobile.
Listen to Chasing Life, streaming now, wherever you get your podcasts.
All right, if you're getting ready, it's 15 minutes past the hour.
Here is your morning roundup.
Some of the stories you need to know to get your day going.
While the rain is over, the danger is not.
Dozens of rivers across the southeast are expected to hit major flood stage this week.
That's adding to the devastation already on the ground.
So for example, in Louisville, river levels rose five feet in 24 hours, and that triggered
a mandatory evacuation order for low-lying communities near the Kentucky River.
It's kind of devastating on that part, you know, it's under siege, basically.
We're lucky enough it's not extremely devastating, but it's hard on a lot of people.
Twenty-four people are now confirmed dead, that's across seven different states.
South Korea announcing it will hold a snap election in June to choose its next leader.
The country's last president was removed just last week by the nation's top port for
trying to impose martial law.
The Trump administration revoking the legal status of migrants who entered the U.S. using
the Biden era CBP1 app as an email from the Department of Homeland Security ordered
them to leave immediately.
It's unclear how many people received the email.
To be clear, more than 900,000 migrants have been allowed to enter the country by making
appointments on the app since 2023.
And a small jet skating off the runway and into the water in Oregon, the plane was cleared
for approach.
The pilot never told controllers they were on the ground.
There were five people on board.
They all have to be taken to the hospital, but for minor injuries.
And you gotta see this.
Not exactly a fan of Boris Johnson, the former British Prime Minister, had a run-in with
an ostrich.
He was driving through a wildlife park in Texas when the animal came up to the window and
hacked his hand.
Johnson's wife posted this video on Instagram with a caption, too funny not to share.
Built to come on CNN this morning sweeping cuts to programs such as meals on wheels,
the potential crisis now facing millions of seniors and disabled veterans.
Also, the Trump administration revoking even more student visas.
Good morning to San Antonio, home of the NCAA championship game was a late night of
partying there for the Florida Gators.
This morning, many programs like meals on wheels are facing an uncertain future, much
like the elderly and disabled Americans who depend on them.
The latest round of dosch cuts hitting the government agency that funds and facilitates
those programs, according to NPR, is going through a reorganization.
Joining me now, the former head of the administration for community living, Alison Barkhoff.
Alison, I think most people don't know that agency very well or what it does.
We're talking about meals on wheels.
I think also LIHEAP correct me if I'm wrong, which helps people get funding for their
heating bills, air conditioning.
What are you hearing from former colleagues about these cuts?
Good morning and thank you for having me.
A lot of people might not know the administration for community living, but it provides tens
of millions of older adults, people with disabilities and family caregivers, life saving services
and supports like meals for older adults, senior centers, family caregiver supports, services
that help people leave institutions like hospitals and nursing homes and go home.
As you mentioned, HHS, the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services announced last
week that the administration for community living would be dismantled and its programs
spread across the department and over half the staff has been terminated.
There's a lot of uncertainty right now about the future of these programs and how they
will be able to continue to support the health, independence and dignity of the millions
of Americans who rely on them day in and day out.
So Alison, just so we're clear, as they said, the programs are not going away.
The programs will be under other departments.
Why can't that work?
There aren't there other agencies.
There's often duplication in the federal government.
What is it that you think will happen if they move to these other departments?
First, we have not had any transparency.
The fact sheet from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services said, quote-unquote
critical programs would be moved.
There's been no information at this point about which programs will continue, which ones
might be eliminated and where they're going.
Secondly, with less than half the staff, it will be nearly impossible to implement these
programs.
In fact, some of the agencies where these programs are being moved also were really cut
to the bone in terms of their staff.
And finally, people are incredibly concerned.
The funding that Congress allocated in mid-March has not yet gone out to the field.
Many of these community-based providers can last no more than two or three weeks without
critical federal funding before they begin to cut services or even start laying off their
own staff.
A lot of uncertainty right now and no information coming out from HHS about exactly what's
happening with these programs.
Allison, we have just a minute left, but I want to get a sense from you where you think
we will see the impact first.
I know a lot of food pantries might be expecting more people to show up, but these are the
communities where often they can't get the help, right?
Maybe they can't drive themselves, they can't do these other things.
So where do you think we're going to see this rear its head in terms of its effects on
everyday people?
I think we are going to start seeing this literally in communities across the country.
People rely every day on the one healthy meal that comes and feeds an older adult.
People rely every day on the person who might come in their home to help get them out
of bed, give them a shower, and get them out into the community.
If we don't see this funding come out soon, we will literally start seeing these life-saving
services reduced, and potentially people having to leave their own homes and communities
and enter nursing homes.
That's how critical the programs, the administration community living provides are to people day
in and day out.
That's Allison Barkoff, a former head of the administration for community living under
President Biden.
Straight ahead on CNN this morning, we're going to talk about the Supreme Court handing
the Trump administration a big win, basically allowing deportations to continue under the
Alien Enemies Act with one distinct condition.
Plus, it is in drinking water all across the country, fluoride.
That might not be the case for long.
The new season of United States of Skandal has bribery, fraud, undercover agents, and
politician suffering from a moral virus, you know, the usual.
United States of Skandal with Jake Tapper, Sunday at 9 on CNN.
It scares the devil out of me.
We have a choice.
We can pay the bills or raise prices or try and absorb them and go out to business.
Businesses in the U.S. that rely on imports from China now scrambling as President Trump
threatens to hike tariffs on China again.
Good morning everybody.
I'm Audit Cornish.
I want to thank you for joining me here on CNN this morning.
It's half past the hour on the East Coast, and here's what's happening right now.
China describing President Trump's new tariffs as economic bullying and they're vowing
to fight to the end despite the new threat markets around the world rising.
U.S. futures pointing up this morning in Asian markets closing in the green.
And Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. wants fluoride out of our drinking
water.
He says he will tell the CDC to stop recommending it to communities that they add the mineral
to their water supply.
And CDC guidelines say fluoride is an effective and cost-effective way to prevent tooth decay.
The Trump administration has revoked the visas of eight more international students in
the past two weeks, nearly 150 students have had visas revoked.
The reason for their alleged involvement in campus protests is not clear that that's
the case in many cases.
Now the Supreme Court is handing the Trump administration a legal victory on its use of
the Alien Enemies Act.
In a split decision, the Justice has lifted an injunction sparked by last month's deportation
flights to a super prison in El Salvador.
The emergency appeal allows the Trump administration to continue using the law from 1798 to speed up deportations.
In her dissent, Justice Sonia Sotomayor calls the administration's actions a quote,
extraordinary threat to the rule of law.
President Trump and his allies see it as vindication.
This decision proves that President Trump and our administration have always been right
from the beginning.
He will continue to utilize the Alien Enemies Act to remove foreign terrorists.
Now there's a catch.
The court's ruling does require the administration to give proper notice to people who may be removed.
We're going to talk about how some of this might work.
Some of the implications with my group chat and you guys this hearing today is going to
be before the judge, in this case, who originally put the injunction on these flights.
Mike Dubkey, people are in the White House obviously seeing this as vindication for the
use of the entire Anemies Aliens Act.
I'm not sure that's the case if you really read the fine print of the rulings, but what
does it mean to be able to talk about this as a victory?
I think they need to talk about this as a victory, but you're absolutely right.
There are now restrictions, but what they were putting forward was that the Anemies Act
doesn't just apply to nation-states.
It applies to gangs, terrorist groups, whatnot.
Trump was elected to lower prices.
He was elected to get tough on immigration and he was elected to get tough on crime.
This covers the efforts that they've had over the last several weeks.
He covers those last two items of getting tough on crime, getting tough on immigration
and sending a message.
In that sense, I think they feel like this is a positive step forward and they can continue
to do what they've been doing now.
They have some new rules and guidelines.
This is the way the Constitution's supposed to work.
So it's a victory for them, but I think it's also a victory for rule of law.
I think that Justice Odomayor says slightly disagrees about that.
I mentioned that, but we have this kind of weird split screen happening, where you have
the administration showing these images from that prison in El Salvador, and then you
have other news organizations, you have people on social media pointing to those cases
where people without due process are caught up in this dragnet, so to speak.
So as this case still works its way through the courts, we were hearing at CNN from the
lawyer of another person who was sent to one of these prisons, and here's what he's
enduring there.
We are gravely concerned for his safety in the sickle.
We know the conditions there.
We know that there are reports of torture, the images of Andri when he arrived there,
what we heard that he was crying for his mom, that he was pleading for help.
I can only imagine how scary this situation is for him.
So this is about a Venezuelan makeup artist who was swept up by the administration with
no hearing because of his tattoos.
They insist that he is a Venezuelan gang member again, because there's no day in court.
We don't know really what's going on.
Chuck, can you talk about how these cases affect the conversation?
Yeah, the American people, to Max Point, they did and want to have a safe U.S.
And almost everyone, including many Democrats, agree, if you come to this country and you
do something violent, let's see the definition of violent, you should probably be deported.
You should probably get your day in court, but you shouldn't be here.
You got an opportunity to come, but what we're learning, which is chilling, is that only
8% of the folks who actually were sent to this prison have a violent crime.
Only 2% have some kind of crime.
That includes parking tickets or speeding tickets.
The vast majority of these people have no criminal record here or at home.
And this does not make it right to send packed people who had violent crimes.
You should send them back.
We are talking about a day in court, just to make sure innocent folks and God forbid an
American citizen or somebody here is here illegally.
It may be a temporary status, but there's lots and lots of immigrants that came here.
Like my family came here who paid taxes, who obeyed by law, because you have to remember
that our immigration system has been broken for a very, very long time.
It's not like when my grandparents came and you just signed in at the border and you got
to come in, there's this long extensive process that makes it almost impossible to come
into this country.
Right.
That's why you saw people coming.
Jumping in here, the CPB1 app, the Biden administration allegedly put in place so that
people could make appointments just so they could go through the process and now that's
being revoked and those people are being told to go home.
So Jackie, as this reaches further and further into the world of people who are trying to
do things legally or getting caught up, what could the ripple effects be?
So I think that there has been, you know, a chilling effect about people trying to come
into this country, we've seen some of those numbers drop, but really just going back
to this case.
I think that this also proves the administration is taking this as a way to consolidate executive
power, which is something that they've really been exerting since this administration came
into being.
But the due process piece is going to be critical and you would assume that the president's
lawyers follow it because the Supreme Court handed it down, but we'll have to wait and
see that that's a big question.
Yeah.
And not going away.
The Supreme Court will be back in a moment.
I'm going to move on to some international news because there was a surprising announcement
from President Trump.
The U.S. and Iran, he claims are already engaged in talks over the country's nuclear program.
Iranian state media reports that their country's foreign minister will meet with a U.S. special
envoy for the Middle East, Steve Wicoff and Oman on Saturday.
I think everybody agrees that doing a deal would be preferable to doing the obvious.
And the obvious is not something that I want to be involved with or frankly that Israel
wants to be involved with if they can avoid it.
So we're going to see if we can avoid it.
But it's getting to be very dangerous to it.
So the last publicly known time that the U.S. and Iran held direct senior-level talks
was a decade ago.
Joining me now is Holly Dagress, senior fellow at the Washington Institute.
Welcome to CNN this morning.
We reached out to you because on Twitter you were talking about how Iran needs a deal
because it is in a dire situation on the ground, right?
Over time sanctions have had their intended effect.
So does that mean it is willing to come to the table?
Adi, thank you for having me on the program.
Well, I think it's not just sanctions that has had its intended effect.
It's actually mismanagement and corruption as well on the part of the Islamic Republic.
And I think that the situation we've seen in Iran for the past few years has suggested
that it's not just a dire economic situation, but that the people are very discontent
to the point that they've been wanting the Islamic Republic gone.
And that's why we saw the 2022 Women Life Freedom uprising happen.
And so I'm given the developments on the ground with the economy,
the discontent from the people, and of course the region,
they are desperate for some kind of economic reprieve
that will help them float for the next four years.
And that's what they're hoping to get through these potential talks
that if they lead to something.
You were talking about how things have changed in the region.
I'm thinking about some military changes like the New York Times,
but at this way they were saying that Iran has lost the air defenses
around its key nuclear sites because of precise Israeli strikes since last October.
And Iran can no longer rely on its proxy forces in the Middle East,
of course, thinking about Syria, et cetera.
So this is this perilous moment militarily as well.
Can you put that in context for us?
Sure, of course, last year we had two tit-for-tat strikes
between Iran and Israel.
Israel had taken out these air defense in Iran.
And what we're seeing is that in just the past few weeks,
U.S. President Donald Trump had sent a letter calling for talks.
And from what we've heard from various sources is that he said,
if you don't do these talks, that there will be some sort of military action
against Iran and that they had a two-month deadline.
And of course, Iran had responded that they would want to indirect talks.
And that's what we've been seeing is actually this potato-potato moment,
which is, are these indirect talks, are these indirect talks?
But at the end of the day, these are talks.
And so that's what's supposed to be happening the Saturday and Oman.
But one thing I want to ask you before I let you go,
which is that there's distrust, obviously, between both countries.
But the U.S. also pulled out of that nuclear deal under Trump.
So is Iran going to the table kind of, yeah, concerned about that?
Does that affect this negotiation going forward?
Well, as you know, the U.S.
which you from the JCPOA in 2018, despite not violating the deal at the time
under the first Trump administration.
And believe it or not, if you remember the talks between Zelensky and Trump just weeks ago,
when that fell apart at the White House, the Iranians were actually quick to react.
There was a billboard in Tehran that basically had the picture of the talk
and it said lessons from Ukraine.
In an essence, it was saying that we shouldn't trust the United States.
So what you're actually going to be seeing is a bit of a divide
on if these talks should even be happening domestically inside Iran
because there are groups in Iran that believe that the United States should never be trusted.
But in this situation, there's going to be a push for talks
because of this situation on the ground.
And they realize that they need some sort of band-aid just to keep a float
to survive the next four years of the Trump administration.
Holly Degress is a senior fellow at the Washington Institute talking to us there
about Iran. Appreciate your time.
Coming up on CNN this morning, we're going to be talking tariff tension
because it is hitting investors and small business owners.
Congressman Chuck Edwards is here.
His constituents with North Carolina are trying to cope with this trade war
while recovering from the effects of a hurricane.
Plus, college basketball crowns and new national champion,
we have the latest from San Antonio.
They've won, they can't touch it.
They can't, won't suck it.
As tariff fears Grip Wall Street, main street is, of course, taking a hit.
Small business owners still reeling from billions of dollars in losses.
For example, from Hurricane Helene and Western North Carolina.
Now tariffs are bringing a new threat to that recovery.
Right now we're under serious strain from tariffs, especially on aluminum.
Most of our BR is put in cans.
And our aluminum prices have increased 17% this calendar year
and are expected to grow even higher.
Absorbing these costs is simply not feasible without raising prices.
These tariffs are pouring salt and a wound that is just now beginning to heal.
I wanted to talk about this because these voices are from North Carolina.
So here is the Republican Congressman Chuck Edwards of North Carolina.
His district, of course, was hit by Helene last year.
Congressman, thank you for being here with me this morning.
Yeah, good morning. Thanks for having me.
So we heard there some small business owners speaking out,
saying specifically, this is how this is going to hurt us.
And then recently we heard from one of your state's Republican senators,
Tom Tilles, who said this about how tariffs might impact farmers in your state.
Anyone who says there may be a little bit of pain before we get things right,
need to talk about farmers who are one crop away from bankruptcy.
They don't have time.
So we've got to be crisp on this implementation.
Otherwise, we can do damage since they're reputable to farmers and businesses.
So the senator is actually pushing a bill in the Senate signing onto a bill
that would rein in the president's tariff power.
Is that something you think the house should consider as well?
Is it something you would sign on to have given the chance?
No, I certainly would not sign on to that theory.
I believe that our president was very clear when he asked to be our president,
that he'd be using tariffs to make America more competitive.
I trust that he will do exactly that.
I know that there's just a lot of angst out there right now,
but we're really early into this process.
These lawmakers are responding to their constituents.
What are you telling these people who say,
look, I am genuinely worried.
I cannot wait until the economy bottoms out
or for manufacturing to be brought back to the US a decades-long process.
Well, the tariff announcements are really young.
We're only into a few days ago they were announced.
I believe that we need to give president the opportunity to bring world leaders
to the table and begin to have discussions
on what we need, what the United States needs from them
to create a more fair and balanced trade atmosphere.
I've got the full confidence that that's exactly what he's going to be able to do.
I believe the American people have full confidence.
They elected President Trump widespread in this country
based on the fact that he told us he'd be leveraging tariffs
to make us more competitive.
I want to talk about the lumber industry,
the US is planning on hiking existing duties
on Canadian lumber up to 34%.
I know lumber exports are a big deal in North Carolina,
so you're going to be facing reciprocal tariffs on that.
And it could also raise basically home-building materials,
raising the average cost of a home by potentially more than $9,000.
Is there anything that you're worried about when it comes to impacts
on people who are in the middle of trying to rebuild after the hurricane?
Yeah, certainly we're all concerned about our world economy right now.
But we have a president that has the courage to stand out in front of the world
and use America's might, not only our military might,
but our economic might to convince the rest of the world
to enter into fair trade agreements.
The announcement of tariffs is only the beginning of this process.
We know that President Trump is the great negotiator.
He's the author of the art of the deal.
I certainly believe that he's trying to create leverage right now
and say to the rest of the world
that America is going to grow our economy.
And can you, Congressman, can I jump in here?
Leverage for what?
It's not clear.
We've heard multiple reasons for the tariffs.
No consistency in the way they're applied.
We were earlier looking at a report out of Russia
where lawmakers there were joking around about the fact
that Russia wasn't facing tariffs.
I think people are trying to make sense of this
and they're having a hard time hearing back
from their representatives.
Trust us, it's going to work out.
Well, let's look back at President Trump's 40th.
His first term when he was...
We know he likes tariffs.
We just don't know what this is supposed to accomplish
and in what time frame and for what specific reasons.
So, again, let's look back while he was our 45th president.
He negotiated deals with countries like Canada and Mexico
using the leverage of tariffs that those countries
in return for us lowering tariffs would
purchase more American agricultural products and goods.
Unfortunately, he did not become the 46th president
and President Biden did not enforce those agreements.
I believe that we're in a position now
where foreign leaders will take him very seriously
and they'll meet up to the agreements
that are ultimately to be made.
The announcement of tariffs is just the beginning.
The real benefit comes after the negotiation,
after foreign leaders come to the table.
Now, I believe that we should get President Trump
the opportunity to bring them to the table.
And yes, we should watch what's taking place
with a great deal of scrutiny, but at this point,
I believe that we need to trust the President.
Congressman Chuck Edwards of North Carolina.
We're going to switch gears now because finally,
the madness is over.
The Florida Gators are the last team standing.
One second, and it's over.
Florida is back on top of the college basketball world.
Florida overcoming a smothering Houston defense
and a 12-point second half deficit
to beat the Cougar 65 to 63 last night.
What does this win mean for you and Gator Nation?
Obviously, we're thrilled, man.
It's a heck of a moment, an incredible opportunity to be here.
And the fact that we finished it up means everything in the world.
I'm joined by CNN contributor, Carrie Champion,
and CNN Sports Anchor, Koi Wire.
I know you guys both watch this closely.
Koi, I'm bringing you because you were up in the mix.
We just saw at the end.
And Carrie, I'm bringing you back because you were like,
Duke's going to take it.
So, first, I just have to get your point of view on where we stand now,
because that did not work out for many reasons.
But how are you feeling about the game you saw?
Is that from your point?
That's for you, Carrie.
Too soon!
I mean, it's fine.
I will take the L.
I'm sure I was like millions of others
who thought Duke would win.
Congratulations to Houston for getting past Duke.
And then I thought Houston would take it all.
So, what I'm feeling right now,
if I'm honest with you, Sarah Cider's going to be insufferable,
because her Florida Gators won,
but they just conferred just a few minutes.
Their defense did in the end,
which is pretty ironic, because Houston is no further defense.
But congratulations.
They did a good job.
Koi, I'll let you have the stage since.
I love that she reminded everyone I had it wrong.
I didn't do it.
That was the girl already.
I mean, I mean, she said it.
Incredible win for Gator Nation.
I mean, this was their first championship in 18 years.
And we're talking about a very storied program.
If you look back when they won,
they're back-to-back titles in 06 and 07.
And the way they won is the most important thing here,
because this was one of the top three offenses
in the nation all year,
but Carrie mentioned that,
suffering Cougars defense.
And that was the first time the Cougars lost all year
when holding an opponent to under 70 points.
But the Gators still find a way to win.
Their star was shut down.
Walter Clayton had zero points in the first half,
but his teammates rallied up.
They rise up around him,
and they find a way to get it done with grit,
with toughness,
walking off the stage there with coach at the end,
literally walking him up the court
for the first time as a national champion.
It was absolute elation.
And he's now the youngest coach
to win a national title in 42 years.
He's just 39 years old,
and I think they've got a pretty good,
dark thing cooking down there in Gainesville.
And Carrie, you know, while I have you,
I also want to talk about the women's champions
with Yukon back on top again.
Why are they so dominant?
What does this moment sort of say about that team?
Yeah, we were in Tampa this weekend for the final four.
I will say this.
Geno Arem, say what you want about him.
He is by far one of the best coaches
to ever do with.
They have 12 national championships.
And the reason why that program is that way is because of him.
He created it 40 years of coaching.
And this is the fiber of that type of team
and that organization.
He's been able to put together such a good program.
And I have to give him all of the credit,
because people decide where they want to go.
And usually they pick Yukon because of what it's known for.
And he's bringing that glory back.
You see him hugging page beckers here.
Page, this is her last year in college.
And I thought it was a beautiful Cinderella story
because she had to fight through injury.
She was the number one in her class in 2020.
And she watched all of her teammates just go away
into the WNBA and do well.
And so now I'm just really, really happy for what I would think
is an appropriate ending for a college superstar
and for Geno Arem and his program.
All right, Carrie, champion and coi wire,
bringing me a little joy this morning
because it's a rough news day.
Thanks you guys.
I know, I know.
Thank you, Adi.
All right.
We're going to talk about what we're keeping an eye on
in the news now.
And I'm going to bring it back to the group.
Jackie, can I start with you?
What are you watching out for the next day or two?
There our page in here was invited
to testify a part of Bill Cassidy's help committee this week.
I'm clear, rather, he's going to accept that invitation.
But, you know, what does this mean for Oversight
of that very critical agency that he leads?
Yeah, a lawmaker who was very skeptical
during those hearings.
Chuck, how about you?
I'm keeping an eye on the stock futures.
Is it going to go up?
Is it going to go down?
It's another rollercoaster day.
But the thing I'm really keeping my eye on is Ted Cruz
because I blame you for my Houston Cougars
losing last night.
Every time you show up at a sporting event
for Texas team, we lose.
And I am bitter and it's your fault.
Yeah, I'm not sure that's how sports work,
but I am new.
I promise you it is.
My last word to you.
All right, that is exactly how sports works.
It's all about superstition.
So, let's go there.
Fair, fair, fair.
I'm in fact checked.
I like it.
I'm looking at the seven senators
who put their names forward of Republican senators
on the bipartisan Trade Review Act of 2025.
I'm looking to see who the next six are.
Because while President Trump has a high threshold for pain,
there's not really a lot of profiles
and courage of the 535 members of Congress.
And several of these people, I think,
are going to step forward Republicans
and put their name to that.
If the stock market continues to go down
or if we have some bad economic messaging.
So, I'm waiting to see where they get to 60.
I know Trump will veto it.
But let's see who joins those seven
who have already signed down on the Republican side.
All right, thanks to the group chat and things
to you for waking up with us.
I'm Adi Cornish and CNN New Central starts right now.
This week on the assignment with me, Adi Cornish.
There are reports of at least a dozen students and faculty
who have been detained by federal agents.
How does this happen?
How can the government detain legal immigrants
without charges?
How is this affecting students and faculty
at campuses around the country?
And who is challenging the government
over potential First Amendment violations
for punishing people who say things
that the administration labels a threat?
Listen to the assignment with me,
Adi Cornish streaming now on your favorite podcast app.