hello lovely students and welcome back to english with lucy a few weeks ago i made a video about
ordering a coffee in advanced c1 c2 english if you watched that video you probably thought
lucy can't take this any further but then i started thinking and my mind turned to mcdonald's
as it sometimes does when i'm really hungry i thought to myself could i possibly take this
concept and make a video about ordering at mcdonald's in super advanced english how far
could i possibly take this oh students have i got a treat for you today before we start i want to
remind you that as always there is a free pdf that goes with this lesson i think you're going to like
it because we go into c1 english in great detail and we include a lot of extra information on the
grammar i'm also going to go through a lot of the advanced vocabulary in this video but the video
would be too long so i'm going to go through a lot of the advanced vocabulary in this video but the
video would be too long so i'm going to go through a lot of the advanced vocabulary in this video but
long if i went through it all so i've put all of the words and phrases i talk about plus more in
that pdf you are going to love it if you'd like to download that just click on the link in the
description box you enter your name and your email address and my free pdf will arrive directly in
your email inbox after that you will automatically receive my free weekly lesson pdfs plus all of my
news course updates and offers it's free you can unsubscribe at any time okay let's get started and
okay let's get started and i need to
address the comment that i anticipate in the comment section lucy no one orders in mcdonald's
like this you're right people don't order from mcdonald's like this and i said in my video about
ordering a coffee that someone would probably spit in my drink if i ordered like that and the same
is true here don't do this to the workers in mcdonald's but today's video is jam-packed with
super advanced vocabulary and grammar structures that we do genuinely use just not necessarily in
this context and i think it's such a fun way to learn them i also have homework for you
at the end of this lesson when you've learnt all the advanced ways of ordering at mcdonald's
i want you to do your go-to order at mcdonald's in a comment make it as advanced as you possibly
can it's going to be hilarious i can't wait to read them okay we have five levels today
let's start with level one can i have a cheeseburger medium fries and a large
coke please you could also use could or may so this is actually how i would
at McDonald's.
Now, I covered the differences
between using the different modal verbs
in my video about ordering a coffee.
So if you're interested, go and watch that.
But you might notice that I ordered fries and not chips,
even though in the UK, we normally say chips.
In McDonald's, we go American and we ask for fries.
We also order Coke, as short for Coca-Cola.
We never tend to say cola.
That's just like an off-brand name to us.
We're also often asked eat in or take away,
meaning are you eating in the restaurant
or taking the food somewhere else?
This is really important because we have different tacks.
It's cheaper to eat food out of a restaurant
than inside a restaurant.
In the US, you're more likely to hear eat in or to go.
So that's my first order, level one, nice and simple.
Now let's move it up a notch, get a bit more advanced.
Level two, what I'd love is a well-done cheeseburger
with a finely sliced, perfectly melted piece of cheese
and a dab of cheese.
A dab of ketchup, freshly made, lightly salted fries
and a large Coke with two cubes
of almost defrosted ice, please.
There's a 20% chance they're gonna spit
in my food at this point.
Okay, first I want to touch on the grammar.
It started with a cleft sentence.
I love cleft sentences.
What I'd love is, what I'd love is.
Instead of saying I'd love a, what I'd love is.
How cool is that?
Okay, we use cleft sentences to place the emphasis
on a certain part.
And in this case, I was emphasising a well-done cheeseburger.
That brings me to the next grammar point, well-done.
Compound adjectives.
Compound adjectives are adjectives
that have two or more words acting as one single descriptor.
Here are some examples from the text.
We have well-done, finely sliced, perfectly melted,
freshly made, lightly salted, well-done, finely sliced.
And almost defrosted.
Now, as you can see, I can preempt this question
in your head right now.
Some are separated by hyphens and others are not.
Why is this?
Well, we often hyphenate compound adjectives
when they come before a noun.
However, we don't hyphenate compound adjectives
when the first word ends in ly, l-y.
We talk a lot more about compound adjectives
in my C1 programme.
By the way, if you didn't know
that I run an online B1, B2, and C1 programme,
I think you'll be pleasantly surprised.
I've got links to them in the description box,
or you can just visit englishwithlucy.com
and see all the information.
Next, I have two pieces of vocabulary
that I want to touch on.
I asked for a dab of ketchup.
A dab is a small amount of something
that is put on a surface quickly.
I dab on makeup, for example,
and I wanted a dab of ketchup, just a little bit.
I also wanted the ice cubes,
almost defrosted, okay?
To defrost means to become warmer,
so it's not frozen anymore.
Finally, I want to talk about the punctuation
I used in that sentence.
Did you notice that I used semicolons
to separate the items in my order?
We can use semicolons to separate items in a list
if at least one of the items already contains a comma.
These two items had commas, as you can see.
Semicolons are really good
at helping avoid confusion in long lists.
Okay.
My order was quite advanced,
but I know I can go a little bit further.
Let's start with level three.
If I may, I would like to ask for a well-done burger
topped with a piece of cheese
that is on the point of melting,
a hint of gherkin, and just a dollop of ketchup.
I've also got a craving for some gently salted fries
with a golden hue,
though under no circumstances should they be burnt,
and nothing would quench my thirst more
than a Coke with crushed ice.
Okay, I'm not gonna lie,
that actually sounds absolutely delicious.
Insufferable, but delicious.
First, I want to talk about the structure
I used to begin my order.
If I may.
This is a very polite way to begin or end a request.
I'd love a cookie, if I may.
Next, there are two grammatical structures
that I want to talk about.
The first one is on the point of,
and this is a phrase to express
that something is about to happen
in the very near future,
on the point of melting,
I'm just about to melt.
Another structure in this sentence,
under no circumstances should they be burnt.
Wow, that does sound really advanced.
We do use this structure though, we do.
What do you notice about the word order here?
This sentence contains another of my favourites.
I can't choose between cleft sentences and inversion.
Inversion is when the verb comes before the subject.
Should they?
But it's not a question.
It's an example of inversion,
after a negative and verbial, under no circumstances.
Again, in my C1 course,
we have a whole section on cleft sentences and inversion.
Now, for some vocabulary.
I asked for a hint of gherkin.
A hint is a very small amount of something,
and a gherkin is a small cucumber
that is preserved in vinegar.
There is a building in London
that everyone calls the gherkin
because it looks like a gherkin.
Did you guess that?
You might already know
the American English word for this, which is pickle.
Pickle for us, although we would understand you
depending on context,
but pickle for us is more like chutney,
something that you serve with cheese.
A cheese and pickle sandwich is very popular
and there are no gherkins in sight.
That's cheese and chutney more than anything.
Next, craving.
A craving is a strong desire for something.
Pregnant women often talk about their cravings.
So weird.
My most consumed fruit is Granny Smith apples.
And only recently,
I found out that my mum had cravings for Granny Smith apples
when she was pregnant with me.
That has to be connected.
Another word was hue,
which means a colour or a shade of a colour.
And finally, I talked about quenching my thirst.
To quench one's thirst means to drink
until one doesn't feel thirsty anymore.
Some gorgeous vocabulary there.
Now let's try level four,
and we're still not at the end yet.
Might I request a burger constructed
of a char-grilled patty, a sliver of cheese,
that is more sharp than pungent,
a gherkin with a bit of a bite, and a dab of ketchup?
That should be served in a lightly toasted bun
with a smattering of sesame seeds.
I've also got a hankering for a generous serving of fries,
which should be nicely crispy.
In fact, so crispy should they be,
that I would like to hear a delicate crunch
as I bite into each one.
I'll top all of that off
with an ice cold glass of Coke, please.
Okay, I draw the line at this one.
I'm going to have to go.
Okay. I'm going to have to go.
What an annoying customer.
Honestly, I would actually like to witness somebody
try this at a McDonald's.
I'd love to see the response.
Now let's look at the language.
First, I started with might I request.
This is a very polite way to say,
can I ask for, or can I have.
We don't tend to use it with please.
You wouldn't say please might I request.
Might I request, or please could I request,
but not together.
I also used an advanced comparative structure.
More sharp,
than pungent.
To compare two similar qualities,
we often use more,
plus adjective,
plus than,
plus adjective.
So I essentially wanted it to be sharp,
not pungent.
I also used inversion,
my favourite again.
So crispy should they be that.
So crispy should they be that,
et cetera, et cetera.
We use inversion when we have so,
plus an adjectival or adverbial phrase,
at the beginning of a sentence for emphasis.
We could rewrite it like this.
They should be so crispy that.
That also makes perfect sense,
but the other one just sounds,
whoa, a little bit more artful.
Now, vocabulary.
There was some really good vocabulary in this.
I asked for a char-grilled patty.
To char-grill means to cook something over a high heat,
so that its surface is slightly burnt,
adding a lot of flavour.
And a patty is a piece of food made into a circular shape,
a raw burger shape.
That's a patty.
Patty is more common in American English,
but it's making its way into British English too,
because we don't have very good food.
So we have to welcome it in from other cultures.
The next two were about cheese,
sharp and pungent.
Sharp means strong and a little bit kind of sour or bitter.
It almost stings your tongue a little bit.
Pungent means having a very strong taste or smell.
It normally implies a negative smell,
unless you're talking about cheese,
where a strong smell is expected.
I also wanted a smattering of sesame seeds on my burger bun.
I can't say that word without smiling.
Smattering, it's so good.
A smattering means a small number or amount.
And finally, I used the phrase to have a hankering for.
My mum uses this all the time.
You can also use it to say, oh, I'm hungry.
You can use it in a phrasal verb format,
to hanker after, to hanker after something.
Both of those mean to have a strong want
or desire for something.
I have a hankering for chocolate.
Okay, number five, level five.
This is as advanced as we're going to get.
This is the height of my powers, okay?
Are you ready?
Because I don't think I am.
Were it not for my intense craving,
I wouldn't be so specific.
However, I would adore a cheeseburger,
a burger bun.
A burger made from meat that has been tenderised by hand
before being fried.
On top of that, I would like some tart cheese,
a smidgen of mustard, a trace of ketchup,
and a perfectly round slice of gherkin.
All of that should be in a bun,
encrusted with sesame seeds.
On the side, I'd like some fries,
which are to have been cooked to a perfect crisp
and dusted with salt.
And finally, I'm going to abstain from drinking anything
as I don't want to ruin my taste buds.
I'm officially insufferable.
Before you throw your phone or your laptop out of the window,
let's look at the language.
Then you can.
Actually, I'm not giving you permission to do that.
That could end in a lawsuit.
I began this order with a conditional sentence,
which was another version of inversion.
Oh, that sounds good.
Another version of inversion.
Another example of inversion.
It's a combination.
Everywhere today.
Were it not for, I wouldn't be.
Now, this is a second conditional
in which the if has been omitted,
making the sentence more formal.
I talk about advanced conditional clauses
in my C1 program in great detail.
I also used a perfect passive infinitive structure.
I'd like some fries, which are to have been cooked.
I must say we don't tend to use this much in spoken English,
which are to have been cooked.
This is the structured be plus to have been
plus the past participle.
I use the passive here
because I don't know who will cook the fries.
Finally, some vocabulary, tart.
Tart, meaning tasting sour or having a bitter taste.
Be careful with the noun version here.
We can have a tart, which is an open pie
normally filled with fruit or sweet food.
And we also have a derogatory word.
If you call someone a tart, well, firstly, don't.
Don't call someone a tart.
A tart is a derogatory term
for a woman showing her sexuality,
maybe dressing in a way that someone feels is inappropriate
or overtly sexual.
The adjective of that is tarty.
I don't recommend you to use it,
but important that you understand it.
Next, we have smidgen, smidgen.
And this means a small piece or amount of something.
I want just a smidgen of wasabi with my sushi.
We also have encrusted, encrusted,
which means covered with something hard.
We often talk about a diamond-encrusted crown
or a bracelet that was encrusted with gemstones.
We have to dust.
So to dust can mean to remove dust from somewhere.
It's a verb for cleaning.
But in this context,
it means to cover something with a powdery substance.
We dust cake with icing sugar,
which is called powdered sugar in American English.
That's something I learned recently, actually,
through following American English.
And finally, we have to abstain, to abstain.
This means to not do something,
especially something pleasurable
that is bad for your health or wrong in some way.
Okay, what did you think of my orders?
I think only the first one would be truly acceptable.
In a McDonald's.
The next four would probably, yeah,
not have a good outcome for me if I did that.
Don't forget about your homework.
I want you to write your homework
or go to McDonald's order in the comment section
and go as advanced as you possibly can.
And don't be afraid of making mistakes.
It's fine.
This is really, really advanced.
So many native speakers would not be able
to explain their use of these structures
and some wouldn't even use them correctly.
Just go for it and have some fun.
And I'll keep my eyes peeled.
I'll be looking in the comment section
to see who takes it to extremes.
You can also use the PDF to help you.
And if you want to download that,
click on the link in the description box.
I've loved today's lesson.
It was ridiculous and fun.
And if you would like another one like this in the future,
please give me some ideas.
We've done coffee.
We've done the daily routine.
We've done McDonald's.
We've done all these things.
What next?
What would you like me to take to extremes for you?
And don't forget to check out my amazing English programmes.
They are 12 week programmes.
We have B1, B2 and C1.
You can see them all at englishwithlucy.com.
Thousands and thousands of students have taken my programmes.
Here are some comments
from students that enrolled in all three programmes.
I must point out Pierre Olivier here
because he writes so incredibly beautifully.
And when I received his testimonial,
I just thought I have to put that in an advanced lesson.
I'd love to have you join them.
I will see you soon for another lesson.
Bye.
selected_model_path: /home/caesar/Downloads/huggingface_downloads//Systran/faster-whisper-large-v3
start: 2025-04-17 07:30:31.562294, end: 2025-04-17 07:32:31.143076
elapse_seconds: 119