hello lovely students and welcome back to english with lucy i have really been enjoying the little
series i'm making about c1 level english advanced english and from your feedback you've been
enjoying it too so today i decided to really push myself and push you too and see if i could write
a lesson about ordering a coffee in english at a c1 level how advanced can we make ordering
a simple cup of coffee oh just watch me it's going to get advanced before we begin as always
i want to let you know that i have lovingly created a free pdf for you it goes with this
lesson it contains all of the phrases and grammatical structures that i'm going to
use in today's video as well as a quiz to test your knowledge just click on the link in the
description box you enter your name and email address you sign up to my mailing list and your
email will arrive directly in your inbox and then after that you've joined my pdf club you will
automatically receive my free weekly lesson pdfs alongside all of my news course updates and offers
you can unsubscribe at any time right let's get started so we all know that ordering a coffee is
one of the first things you learn in english and it can be very simple can i have a coffee please
this way of ordering a coffee is absolutely fine it's perfect in fact although it probably
wouldn't work in somewhere like starbucks where an order is more like can i get a doppio half-calf
skinny mocha venti to go i know i do but that's not what we're talking about today i want to order
a normal coffee in advanced english and i know what some people are going to say when they hear
my order people never speak like that i agree i agree it's not necessary but it's fun and it's
cool and if we can't have fun cool english lessons then what have we got
i think it's fun to see how far we can take it and more importantly for you i think it's a fun and
memorable way to introduce some advanced grammatical structures and vocabulary are you ready
we're going to move up through the levels level one black coffee please this is the simplest way
to order a coffee and it's perhaps not the most polite way to order in a coffee shop but if you're
ordering as part of a group after dinner for example i think it's fine the addition of please
at the end though is important
let's take it up a notch level two can i have a black coffee please here the request is formulated
as a question using the modal verb can which makes it more polite than the first one you will often
hear this said as can i get a black coffee please this is slightly more common in american english
but it's making its way into british english some people don't like the use of get here
but a lot of native speakers use it now let's say this more politely
level three may i please have a black coffee with a splash of milk all right we're getting a little
bit more complex here this is a very polite way to order a coffee using the modal verb may you can
also replace may with the modal verb could which is a more polite way to make requests than can
you can also see that the word please has moved from the end to directly after may i this front
loading of please emphasizes the politeness of the request
we are also now asking for a splash of milk and a splash means a small amount of liquid
of you can use a brackets now it's a интonation right so a recursive application of a fast
and heavy milk that releases small amounts of liquid into a soften milk
from the outside and sets a formal tone from the outset
we are also now asking for a splash of milk and a splash means a small amount of liquid
three and instead of please we can see the adverb kindly this is another way to soften a request and
make it more polite let's add a little more advanced language level five would it be possible
for you to brew a medium-sized black coffee with a splash of milk two sugars and a sprinkling of
cinnamon on top all right this one is even more polite and a bit poetic as well would it be
possible is a very polite way to form a question we also have some more advanced vocabulary
including to brew meaning to make a hot drink like coffee or tea and sprinkling
which means a small amount of liquid or powder that is dropped onto a surface
can i make it even more advanced level six and we're not even at the end yet
if it's not too much trouble could you please craft a medium-sized black coffee
enriched with a splash of a
organic milk, and precisely two cubes of raw sugar
while ensuring it's brewed to the optimum temperature,
and then garnish it with a delicate sprinkling
of cinnamon on top.
We're moving into nightmare customer territory now.
If it's not too much trouble is a very polite way
of asking someone to do something,
we often add it to the beginning of a request,
often when we know the request
is going to cause some extra effort.
Now we're asking for the barista to craft the coffee,
not just make one, craft.
This means to make objects in a skilled way,
especially with your hands.
And the coffee is to be enriched with a splash of milk.
To enrich means to make the quality of something better
by adding something else.
Then it is to be brewed to the optimum temperature.
Optimum means best possible.
You might hear the synonym optimal or optimal
used in American English.
And then we have,
garnished with cinnamon.
To garnish means to decorate food or drink
with a small amount of food.
Can this customer get any worse?
Yes, the answer is yes.
If you've ever worked in retail or hospitality,
you know the answer is yes.
Here is my coffee order in its final form, level seven.
Would you be so kind as to commence the artisanal preparation
of a medium sized black coffee
with a coffee with a single origin beans
and brewed at precisely 89 degrees Celsius?
It should be complemented with a splash of organic,
locally sourced milk,
sweetened to a modest degree
with exactly two cubes of raw sugar
and adorned with a subtle yet discernible sprinkling
of hand ground cinnamon.
Finally, because I'm not done yet,
I request that it be presented in a ceramic mug
featuring a handle ergonomically designed for a right-handed individual.
I would like to see a copy of this recipe in my next video.
Someone is definitely going to spit in this customer's coffee.
Let's look at the grammar.
Would you be so kind as to,
is a very, very polite and formal way to make a request.
And in the final sentence, you saw the structure,
I request that it be presented.
This sentence uses the subjunctive mood,
which is a formal structure in English
and appears after certain verbs like request.
And the vocabulary, first there is to commence,
which means to begin.
We had artisanal, artisanal,
meaning prepared in a traditional way.
We have complimented.
This is the verb to compliment with an E.
It's different to the one with I.
If one thing compliments with an E,
another, it goes well with the other thing
and it makes it better.
We compliment each other, we go well together,
we make each other better.
We compliment each other means we give each other compliments.
I like your dress.
I like your hair.
I like your coffee.
What did you ask for?
I'm gonna ask for that.
Little did she know.
We also have adorned with.
The verb to adorn means to add something decorative
to a person or thing to make it more attractive.
We also have the adjectives subtle and discernible.
Subtle means not obvious or noticeable,
while discernible means able to be recognised.
So I wanted it subtle, but discernible.
And finally, perhaps the most egregious request,
an ergonomically designed handle.
Ergonomically means in a way that makes something,
often equipment or furniture,
comfortable and effective for people who use it.
You'll see all of this grammar,
all of the vocabulary along with example sentences
in the PDF that goes with this lesson.
So remember to download that by clicking the link down below.
What did you think of my sentence?
What did you think of my C1 level coffee order?
Is it realistic?
No.
Is it interesting?
I think so.
And I hope it will help you to remember
some of the structures and vocabulary that I've presented.
We really do use all of these words and phrases in real life.
I really hope you enjoyed this lesson.
If you have any requests for future C1 level
ridiculous videos, please let me know in the comments.
I love writing and making these.
One other thing you might be interested in
especially if you're interested in English at this level.
I have a really gorgeous C1 programme.
It's 12 weeks long.
You can start it immediately.
Over 2000 students have taken this course
and they have had fantastic results.
Look at the feedback from some of my amazing C1 students.
My team and I poured our heart and soul into this course.
We worked a story throughout all of the readings
and listenings.
We injected a lot of humour.
We've even got an entire module on British English humour.
We weave pronunciation throughout the course.
We have weekly conversation lessons
where you listen in on conversations I've had
with really interesting people
and then we break them down and analyse them.
The conversations, not the people.
The people stay intact.
If you're interested in learning a little bit more
visit englishwithlucy.com.
All of my courses are there.
Check out the C1 programme.
I will see you in the next lesson.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
selected_model_path: /home/caesar/Downloads/huggingface_downloads//Systran/faster-whisper-large-v3
start: 2025-04-17 07:24:18.249128, end: 2025-04-17 07:26:07.359032
elapse_seconds: 109